<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="ingrid-portal-help.xsl" ?>
<help>
    <chapter>
        <header>Help for PortalU</header>
        <section help-key="index">
            <header>Help for PortalU</header>
            <content>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=about-1">About PortalU</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-1">Search</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-topics-1">Topics</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-service-1">Service</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-measure-1">Data</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-chronicle-1">Almanac</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=maps-1">Maps</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=rss-news-1">News</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ingrid-inform-1">PortalU informs</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=myingrid-1">My PortalU</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ingrid-newsletter-1">Newsletter</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>About PortalU</header>
        <section help-key="about-1">
            <header>Concept and tasking of PortalU</header>
            <content>
                <p>PortalU, Germany’s environment portal, provides a central 
				point to access 3 million intent pages as well as about 500.000 
				catalogue- and data base entries of public institutions and 
				organisations in the Federation, the Federal States and the 
				Local Authorities. With a mix of current news, environmental 
				readings (e.g. current ozone concentration in the air, water quality), 
				background information and historic environment events, PortalU is aimed 
				at interested lay persons as well as the specialist audience. 
				The information provided is being continually added to with the aim of 
				capturing all official providers of environment information over the long term.</p>
                <p>The EU environment guideline of 2003 and the planned INSPIRE guideline played an important role in the conception of PortalU. These guidelines lay down new standards for the public dissemination of official environment information respectively the construction of the information technology infrastructures necessary for this. In future, signficantly more authorities and organisations than heretofore will be obliged to provide data relevant to the environment in a clear understandable and easily accessible form</p>
                <p> PortalU and the software especially developed for the construction of the portal ”InGrid<sup>®</sup>” were especially conceived as tools to support the authorities in implementing the guidelines. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-2">
            <header>The PortalU operators</header>
            <content>
                <p> PortalU was developed as a follow-up project of the environment data catalogue (UDK) and of the German Environmental Information Network (gein) within the framework of the Federal Republic of Germany Federal States administration agreement (VwV, Verwaltungsvereinbarung) UDK/GEIN entwickelt. The Federal Ministry for the Environment, Nature Conservation and Nuclear Safety (BMU) and the environment ministries of 16 German Federal States were signatories to the administration agreement. PortalU is looked after from a technical and contents point of view by the Coordination Center PortalU in the Lower Saxony ministry for environment and climate protection in Hanover.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-3">
            <header>Function overview</header>
            <content>
                <p>
                    <b>Search:</b> Central function of the Portal is the PortalU-Search (<a href="?hkey=search-1">Search</a>),
                    with the help of which web pages and data base entries can be searched via a customary full text search (<a
                        href="?hkey=search-1">Basic search</a>), but can also be searched using a differentiated specialist vocabulary  (<a href="?hkey=ext-search-1">Advanced Search</a>). </p>
                <p>
                    <b>Service:</b> Here you can find news and information about events and current publications in the environment field.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>Topics:</b> The PortalU topic pages provide a topic-based access to selected, particularly interesting information and data (topic pages).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>Data</b>: PortalU keeps you informed around the clock about the current state of your environment (readings).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>Maps</b>: A maps viewer offers the possibility of entering spatial references for the search via interactive maps or else to display digital maps from the search results list directly in PortalU.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>Almanac</b>: When did the Kyoto protocol come into effect? You can find an answer to this and many other questions on historical environment events in the environment chronicle (environment almanac)..</p>
                <p>
                    <b>News</b>: Current reports are displayed directly from the public relations departments of the participating authorities and organisations.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-4">
            <header>Information sources in PortalU</header>
            <content>
                <p>PortalU is a convenient and user-friendly portal to environment information in the internet. In contrast to most portals and search engines, PortalU gathers not only web pages, text documents and other internet formats but can also access databases and specialist information systems, even when these are not online. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-5">
            <header>Conditions for the use and participation in PortalU</header>
            <content>
                <p>The circle of information providers in PortalU restricts itself mainly to authorities and organisations closely connected with the authorities in Germany, but is being continually expanded. If your organisation would likewise like to make environmentally relevant information available, please contact the Coordination Center PortalU  <a
                        href="http://www.kst.portalu.de/"
                        target="_new">Koordinierungsstelle PortalU</a>.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-6">
            <header>InGrid &#8211; the software behind PortalU</header>
            <content>
                <p>The InGrid<sup>®</sup> software package was developed to realise PortalU. InGrid<sup>®</sup> is positioned on modular and flexible system architecture based on licence-free open source products. This way it becomes possible to adapt the technical structure of the environment information net to changing organisational specifications. Thus, if needed, regional environment portals, e.g. for individual German Federal States or Local Authorities can be created with minimal technical expense. Thanks to Open Source the follow up use of the software is license free and free of cost for partners of the VwV UDK/GEIN.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Search</header>
        <section help-key="search-1">
            <header>Basic search</header>
            <content>
                <p>When you use the search function you can enter one or more search terms. Those pages that contain all search terms will be found.</p>
                <p>Depending on the setting, one of the following search areas will be searched:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Environmental Information: official information on the environment</li>
					<li>Laws: information on legally relevant topics</li>
                    <li>Research Projects: projects on environment research</li>
                    <li>Addresses: responsibilities</li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-2">
            <header>Further topics for the search</header>
            <content>
                <p>In addition to the basic search you can further refine your search. Read the following topics on this::</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ext-search-1">Advanced search for environment information </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ext-search-address-1">Advanced search for addresses </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a
                            href="?hkey=ext-search-research-1">Advanced search for research projects </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a
                            href="?hkey=ext-search-law-1">Advanced search for laws </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-history-1">History </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-settings-1">Options </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-tipps-1">Tips </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-save-1">Save Query</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-expert-1">Expert Entry </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-results-1">Search result list </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-catalog-1">Data Catalogues </a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search for Environmental Information</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-1">
            <header>Advanced search for environmental information</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can refine your search for environmental information via the <i>Advanced Search</i> option.</p>
                <p>In principle, a search term is composed from individual search terms, which are connected by the operators (AND, OR, NOT). You can read about how you can enter these operators manually in the chapter <a href="?hkey=search-expert-1">Expert Entry </a>.</p>
                <p>The <i>Advanced Search</i> offers you the possibility of constructing your search term using a wizard.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-2">
            <header>Areas for specifying the search</header>
            <content>
                <p>The so-called search area embraces all web pages, documents etc. which are captured by a search query. The following areas are available to you to expand or restrict the search area:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ext-search-subject-1">Topic</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ext-search-spacial-1">Space</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ext-search-time-1">Time</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ext-search-area-1">Search-Area</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced: Topic</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-subject-1">
            <header>Search terms</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can add well directed one or several search terms to your search term by linking it with one of the following options:</p>
                <p>
                    <b>all search terms (AND):</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>all</b> the terms entered (standard).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>one of the search terms (OR):</b>  a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>at least one</b> of the terms entered.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>the exact search string:</b>a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>exactly </b>the word group entered (in the same sequence, with spaces etc.).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>none of the search terms:</b> a piece of information will only be found if it contains <b>none</b> of the terms entered.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-subject-2">
            <header>Thesaurus (Specialist Dictionary)</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can add specialist terms to your search term via the specialist dictionary. To do this you put any term into the entry field and send a query to the <a href="#ext-search-subject-3">Thesaurus</a>.</p>
                <p>You will then receive a series of <a
                        href="#ext-search-subject-5">similar terms</a>,which you can add to the search term. You can further specify your search term by clicking on a similar term.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-subject-3">
            <header>Thesaurus</header>
            <section help-key="ext-search-subject-4">
                <header>What is a Thesaurus?</header>
                <content>
                    <p>Like a dictionary, a thesaurus consists of specialist terms on a certain subject area. In addition to the correct spelling, a thesaurus also contains information whether and how a term can be generalised (superordinate terms), specialised (subordinate terms) or expressed in another way (synonyms). Thesauri are used, for example, for indexing keywords and finding documents. </p>
                    <p>PortalU uses the environment thesaurus (UMTHES<sup>®</sup>) of the Federal Ministry of the Environment in Dessau. It contains more than 30,000 specialist terms from the &quot;Environment&quot;subject area.</p>
                    <p>The UMTHES<sup>® </sup>is made available via the <a
                            href="http://www.semantic-network.de/"
                            target="_new">Semantic Network Service (SNS)</a> vom
                        by the Federal Environment Agency (Umweltbundesamt).</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-subject-5">
                <header>Similar Terms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>After your search terms are analysed by the SNS, similar terms are displayed from the thesaurus. You can highlight one or more of these terms and adopt them in your search term (<i>Add to Query</i>).</p>
                    <p>However, you also have the possibility of further specifying a <i>similar term</i> by clicking on the respective term. It will then be shown as a  <a
                        href="#_Thesaurus-Schlagwort">thesaurus-keyword</a>. In addition, the associated  <a
                            href="#_Oberbegriffe"> superordinate</a>-, <a
                        href="#_Unterbegriffe"> subordinate</a>- and <a
                            href="#_Verwandte_Begriffe">related terms</a>
                        will be displayed as well as the  <a href="#_Synonyme">synonyms</a>.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="_Thesaurus-Schlagwort">
                <header>Thesaurus Keyword</header>
                <content>
                    <p>This is the thesaurus keyword currently set. You can adopt it into your search term by crossing it and clicking on the <i>Add to Query</i> button</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="_Oberbegriffe">
                <header>Superordinate Terms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>A superordinate term is a term that generalises a thesaurus keyword. UMTHES<sup>®</sup> provides the possibility of a thesaurus term having several superordinate terms.</p>
                    <p>You can add the superordinate term(s) to your search term by crossing it and clicking on the <i>Add to Query</i> button.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="_Unterbegriffe">
                <header>Subordinate Terms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>A subordinate term is a term that makes a thesaurus keyword more specific. A thesaurus term can possess as many subordinate terms as desired.</p>
                    <p>You can add one or more subordinate terms to your search term by crossing them and clicking on <i>Add to Query</i> button.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="_Verwandte_Begriffe">
                <header>Related Terms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>EA related term is a thesaurus term that is connected with the thesaurus keyword, but is neither a super- nor a subordinate term. A thesaurus term can possess any number of related terms.</p>
                    <p>You can add one or more related terms to your search term by crossing them and clicking on the <i>Add to Query</i>.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="_Synonyme">
                <header>Synonyms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>A synonym is an alternative expression, but one with the same meaning for the thesaurus keyword.</p>
                    <p>Sometimes a synonym consists of two or several thesaurus terms. In this case, the synonym is not to be understood as an alternative expression for a single thesaurus term but as a synonym for the combined term.</p>
                    <p>You can add one or more synonyms to your search term by crossing them and clicking <i>Add to Query</i> button.</p>
                    <p>If you click on the synonym term then you will reach the thesaurus terms behind. You can also adopt these in your search expression.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search: Space</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-1">
            <header>Space</header>
            <content>
                <p>Via the <a
                    href="#ext-search-spacial-3">Gazetteer</a> [environment] of the Federal Environment Agency (Umweltbundesamt) in Dessau-Rosslau, PortalU analyses for every web page, which is made available by PortalU, the according spatial reference. This spatial reference is used in PortalU whithin the framework of the area search. Therefore, the area search is not, as in most other search engines, a full text search for spatial terms.</p>
					<p>In the connected databases the area search takes place by browsing the area attributes entered there.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-2">
            <header>Restricting area <i>By Geographic Name</i></header>
            <content>
                <p>You can add geographical terms in a targeted way to your search term via conceptual area restriction. To do this you enter any term (e.g. Berlin) into the entry field and send a query to the  <a
                    href="#ext-search-spacial-3">gazetteer</a> (Button <i>Look-up Geographic Names</i>). Thereby a query to the Geo-Thesaurus is started. You then receive a listing of Geographical Names, which you can add to the search term. </p>
                
				<p>If you want further to specify your search term, click on a geographic name (e.g. <i> Berlin country</i>) in the result list. You then receive a list of <i>Spatial Relations</i>. These have a spatial relation to the original search result.</p>
            </content>
            <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-3">
                <header>What is a gazetteer?</header>
                <content>
                    <p>Just like the place index of an atlas, the Environment gazetteer (EGT) depicts the names of communities, rivers, mountains, landscapes and other geographical objects in Germany. In so doing, the EGT gives the exact spelling as well as the geographical position (coordinates) of a place.</p>
                    <p>For practical reasons, the EGT is restricted to places, which are normally depicted on maps from the scale 1:250,000. At present, approximately 50,000 geographical objects are depicted in it. The Environment gazetteer is made available via the  <a
                            href="http://www.semantic-network.de/"
                            target="_new">Semantic Network Service (SNS)</a> of the Federal Environment Agency (Umweltbundesamt).</p>
                </content>
            </section>
			<section help-key="ext-search-spacial-4">
                <header>Pocedure in PortalU</header>
                <content>
                    <p>The search term that you have sent off via the <i>Search geographical names</i> button is analysed by the SNS and you receive a series of geographical names by return. You can now add a cross to these and add them to your search term. The geographical names are used to search for an area in the area information of the web pages and the data bases. </p>
                    <p>If you want to further refine your area search terms then you can look at the positional relationships by clicking once on the respective term.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-5">
                <header>Spatial Relations</header>
                <content>
                    <p>After clicking on a geographical name (e.g. Berlin, county), the positional relationships to this 
					name are displayed. By selecting (clicking on) positionally relevant geographical names you can further 
					concretise the spatial reference desired.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-6">
            <header>Restricting Area <i>By Map</i></header>
            <content>
                <p>The PortalU search can be restricted as to area not only via terms but also by selecting a map section (bounding box). When you have defined a suitable bounding box, a targeted search runs over the web provision made available via PortalU for area terms (such as, for example, towns, mountains etc.) that are found in the map section. In the databases available via PortalU, the map section (search rectangle) is searched for directly.</p>
                <p>For orientation and specifiation of a map section you can use the background maps service (Web Map Service) of PortalU or use external map services.</p>
			
            </content>
           <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-7">
				<header>Menu</header>
                <content>
                    <p>In the PortalU map viewer available, as well as activated map services, keys and a metadatasearch are provided in an accordion men, which is situated to the left of the map. By clicking on a menu heading the respective menu item will be opened up.</p>
					<p><img border="0" width="130" height="111"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image201eng.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>		
                    <p><b>Legend</b></p>
                    <p>In the menu item <i>Legend</i> all the keys available are displayed for the map layers activated under<i>Active Services</i> and which are depicted in the map viewer. The legend description provides information which symbols and/or colours are used for the different information displayed in the map.</p>
                   <p><b>Active Services</b></p>
                    <p>All map services, which are found under <i>Active Services</i>, can be activated or de-activated by one click in map viewer. The map services with their layers are represented in a tree structure. </p>
									   
					<p>The individual symbols have the following meaning:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image101.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Moves the selection up</b> : highlighted service or a marked layer is moved up one level. A service or layer can be highlighted by one click with the left mouse button on the name. As regards depiction in the map: layers that are listed further down in the tree structure overlay layers that are listed further down. </p>								
                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image102.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Moves the selection down:</b> A highlighted service or layer is displaced downwards by one level. A service or layer can be highlighted by one click with the left mouse button on the name. When a layer is overlaid by another then this can be made visible by being pushed downwards. The layer that is at the bottom of the list is always depicted as the topmost layer in the map.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image114neu.png"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Removes the selected WMS:</b> A highlighted service or layer is deleted from the ?active services" area. A service can be highlighted by one click with the left mouse button on the name. The removal of single layers is not possible. </p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="20" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image106.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>  	Active Services</b> : The folder symbol is used to display the map services. In the individual folders are to be found the corresponding layers of a service. With one click (left mouse button) on the folder symbol you can move the service, remove it or alter its transparency.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image107.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Active Services</b>: This symbol is used to display a layer. With one click (left mouse button) on the symbol you can move the service, zoom in to the level of the service or call up information.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="17" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image108.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>  	(De)activate this service </b>: If the left check box is ticked for a service or a layer, the service or the layer in the map is activated and depicted in the map if the corresponding zoom level (pre-defined standard of the layer) is set. If the map section depicted is outside the zoom level of the layer then the layer is not displayed in the map and the layer title is depicted in grey. If the tick for a service is removed then all the layers of the service are de-activated.  </p>

					<p> <img border="0" width="18" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image104.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Show metadata:</b>  	Further information (metadata) about a service and/or a layer is displayed for Web Map Services, which are entered below Topics or Federation/Ferderal States. The information, which originate from the particular GetCapabilities-URL, are readout from the data base of the PortalU - Map viewer. If in the GetCapabilities-URL specific data as e.g. to the organisation or address are lacking, some fields can not be filled.</p>

					<p><b>Topics</b></p>
                    <p>Under topics you will find various map services of the Federation and Federal States sorted according to environment topics, which can be loaded into the PortalU map viewer.</p>
                   					   
					<p>The symbols used have the following meaning:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="17" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image109.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> The folder symbol is used for displaying the individual environment topics. In the folder you will find the corresponding map services.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="22"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image111.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding service will be added to the active services and the map section depicted by the service will be zoomed in on in the map.  </p>
 					<p>Note: If the service contains fewer than 5 layers all the layers will be activated directly in the map as well. Should the service contain more than 5 layers then the layers will not be automatically activated. </p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image104.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Show metadata:</b> Further information (metadata) about a service and/or a layer is displayed for Web Map Services, which are entered below Topics or Federation/Ferderal States. The information, which originate from the particular GetCapabilities-URL, are readout from the data base of the PortalU - Map viewer. If in the GetCapabilities-URL specific data as e.g. to the organisation or address are lacking, some fields can not be filled. </p>

                    <p><b>Federation /Federal States</b></p>
                    <p>Under <i>Federation /Federal States</i> you will find environmentally-relevant map services of different institutions and organisations of the Federation and the Federal States sorted on a regional basis (according to Federation and Federal States).</p>
                    
					<p>The meaning of the individual symbols is described under the <i>Topics</i> menu item (see above).</p>
						
                    <p><b>Metadatasearch</b></p>
                    <p>In <i>Metadatasearch</i> you can search for map services of the Federation and Federal States which are incorporated in the PortalU map viewer. Enter a search term for this and click on <i>OK</i>. </p>
                    			
					
					<p>In the search results list the following symbols are used:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="15" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image110.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding layer is added to the active services. </p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="22"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image111.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding layer is added to the active services and the map section described by the layer is zoomed in on. </p>
					<p> With one click on the name of the service and/or of the layer further information on the service and/or layer is displayed.	</p>
                 </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-9">
                <header>Spatial constraints</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you have chosen a map section you can select in which form the area restriction is to be used for the PortalU search. Here the following options are possible:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>1.	The spatial footprint of the result is contained in the search area.</li>
                        <li>2.	The spatial footprint of the result intersects the search area.</li>
                        <li>3.	The spatial footprint of the result contains the search area.</li>
                    </ul>
					                    <p> <img border="0" width="455" height="252"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image208eng.jpg"
                        alt="*"/></p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-10">
                <header>Tool Bar</header>
                <content>
                   <p>Via the tool bar you can either perform various actions directly or do so with one click in the map. </p>
                   <p> <img border="0" width="356" height="35"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image209.jpg"
                        alt="*"/></p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Area constraint: Select search area</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image029.png"
                        alt="*"/> With this button a map section (bounding box) can be selected. After activating the button you can click on a point in the map and, by holding down left mouse button draw up a rectangle. After then letting go of the button the coordinates of the bounding box are displayed underneath the map.</p>
                    <p>By clicking on the<i> Add to Query</i> button the coordinates of the selected map section are added as an area restriction to the search term.</p>
					<p>
                        <b>Area constraint: Select district area</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image028.png"
                        alt="*"/> After selection the administrative unit chosen is displayed under the map. With one click on the <i>Add to Query</i> button the unit will be added to the search term as an area restriction.</p>					
                    <p>
                        <b>Add External Services </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image024.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By means of this button you can add any GetCapabilities-URL (external service) to the active services. 
					</p>
					<p> The layers of the service can be activated directly. Furthermore you can zoom in the map section of the service. Therefor the adequate checks have to be placed (check box).</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Show Data</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image026.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> Which information is displayed depends on for which layer under <i>Active Services </i>the check box has been activated (see above). At present not all services support this function.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Display Coordinates </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image027.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By means of this button point coordinates can be called up in the map. The position of the mouse is displayed in geographical coordinates under the map. The coordinates of the last click in the map are also displayed. .</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Zoom in </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image031.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With this button you can zoom in on the map. You can draw up a map section by holding down the left mouse button to draw up a rectangle. The map is centered on this section and correspondingly enlarged.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Zoom out </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image032.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With one click on this button the map is reduced by a half.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Move Map</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image033.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> Via this button the map can be dragged. To drag: With the left mouse button click on a point in the map, hold the button down and pull the mouse over the map. After this process, the point on the map on which you clicked is then found to be located where you let go of the left mouse button. </p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Back</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image034.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking on this button, the map section, which was displayed before the last action, is restored.</p>
                    <p>The action can be carried out several times in succession.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Forward</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image035.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> If you have gone back to a map section, which lies one or more actions back, using the <i>Back</i> button, you can leaf forward again through the actions you performed after that using the <i>Forward</i> button. The action can be performed as often as the<i>Back</i> action was performed previously.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Show Original Map</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image037.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking this button the zoom area of the original map is restored.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Print</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image039.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking on this button a PDF document of the map is produced with or without a key. You can choose the alignment of the map and also add a title and a commentary to the map. You can print the document via the usual PDF functionality or save it.</p>
						
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search: Time</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-time-1">
            <header>Time</header>
            <content>
                <p>PortalU is able to search for the time references of the connected systems. For this, on the one hand, the data are used that the  <a
                        href="http://www.semantic-network.de/"
                        target="_new">Semantic Network Service (SNS)</a> of the Federal Environment Agency (Umweltbundesamt) has analysed from the web pages as time references. On the other hand, the time references in the databases are accessed. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-time-2">
            <header>Temporal Search</header>
            <content>
                <p>As a time reference you can either give a time frame (From/To) or a point in time (On the). In both cases the format for giving the date is DD.MM.YYYY, that is two figures for the <b>D</b>ay, two for the <b>M</b>onth and four for the <b>Y</b>ear. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-time-3">
            <header>Expansion of search interval</header>
            <content>
                <p>Basically all pieces of information are always found if their time reference is within the search intervals you have entered. By crossing boxes you can also find information to which the following apply: </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The time reference of the results intersects the search interval entered..</li>
                    <li>The time reference of the results encloses the search interval entered.</li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-time-4">
            <header>Temporal Reference</header>
            <content>
                <p>If you are searching for a date connected with an event of relevance to the environment (e.g. the climate conservation conference in Kyoto), by giving a search term you can search for the event in the Almanac (environment chronicle). All events found by the search are displayed. Using the copy and paste functions of your browser you can paste the data given directly into the time reference field you desire.</p>
            </content>
            <section help-key="ext-search-time-5">
                <header>What is the Almanac (Environmental Chronicle)?</header>
                <content>
                    <p>The environmental chronicle is a collection of current and historical events that have significantly influenced our environment situation. As well as the dates of the events, a short description is given of the events as appropriate. </p>
                    <p>The environment chronicle is being made available via the <a
                            href="http://www.semantic-network.de/"
                            target="_new">Semantic Network Service (SNS)</a>of the Federal Environment Agency (Umweltbundesamt) in Dessau-Rosslau.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-time-6">
                <header>Environment events</header>
                <content>
                    <p>All environment events that were found via the search in the almanac (environment chronicle) will be displayed with title and date. By clicking on the event or the plus sign in front of it <img border="0" width="9"
                            height="9"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image018.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> the description of the event will be faded in, and faded out again by clicking on the minus sign
                            <img border="0" width="9" height="9"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image019.jpg"
                        alt="*"/>.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search: Search-Area</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-area-1">
            <header>Content</header>
            <content>
                <p>Here you can ascertain whether you want to search through all environment information (also environmental topics and service) or whether you would only like to search in the environmental topics or only in the press pages (press releases, publications and events).</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-area-2">
            <header>Data Sources</header>
            <content>
                <p>In addition to web servers, metadatasystems and specialist data systems are also connected to PortalU. You can choose whether you want to search in all these systems (standard), or whether you would like to restrict your search in a targeted manner to one or several kinds of data sources.</p>
                <p>If you limit your search to metadata then you also have the possibility of selecting the classes of metadata that you would like to search. The following classes are available to you:</p>
                <ul>
								
					
                    <li>Organisational Unit / Task</li>					
                    <li>Geo-Information / Map</li>
					<li>Document / Report / Literature</li>
					<li>Geo-Service</li>					
                    <li>Enterprise / Project / Program</li>
					<li>Data Pooling / Data Base</li>
                    <li>Service / Application / Information System Datensammlung/Datenbank</li>                  

                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-area-3">
            <header>Federation/Federal States</header>
            <content>
                <p>The data provided in PortalU come from authorities and those organisations closely associated with authorities in the Federal Republic of Germany and the Federal States. You can limit the information provided for your search to the Federal Republic or individual Federal States. It is also possible to choose several items.</p>
                <p>The Federal Republic and also most of the Federal States have several data providers. These are displayed if you click on the plus sign <img border="0" width="9" height="9"
                        src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image018.jpg"
                    alt="*"/> Instead of the Federal Republic or a Federal State, individual providers can also be selected. In this case too, a multiple selection is possible.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Search History</header>
        <section help-key="search-history-1">
            <header>Search History</header>
            <content>
                <p>PortalU stores a history of your search queries. As well as this history, which is automatically carried for one session, you can also as a logged in user (see <a
                        href="?hkey=myingrid-1">myPortalU</a>) save search queries permanently.</p>
                <p>You can call up both forms of stored search queries again via the <i>Search History</i> function.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-history-2">
            <header>Your last search queries submitted</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area your last search queries submitted are listed. By clicking on a search query this is then loaded in the search window and the search is carried out.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-history-3">
            <header>Your saved search queries</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area your permanently saved search queries will be listed. By clicking on a search query this is then loaded into the search window and the search is carried out. Saved search queries can be removed by putting a cross and then using the <i>Delete</i> button.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Options</header>
        <section help-key="search-settings-1">
            <header>Options</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can control the display of search results under the <i>Options</i> heading. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-settings-2">
            <header>Search Results Sorting and Grouping </header>
            <content>
                <p>You can have your search results displayed either according to ranking (relevance of the page found to your search term) or according to newness (the newest pages will be at the top).</p>
                <p><i>Grouping</i> means that the search results are displayed compiled according to <i>Federal Republic/Federal States</i>, <i>Information Providers</i> or <i>Domains</i>.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-settings-3">
            <header>Include similar terms in search</header>
            <content>
                <p>PortalU not only carries out the usual indexing found in search engines but also has the page contents analysed by the <a href="http://www.semantic-network.de/"
                        target="_new">Semantic Network Service (SNS)</a> of the Federal Environment Agency (Umweltbundesamt). As a result of this analysis specialist terms from the <a
                    href="?hkey=ext-search-subject-4">Environment Thesaurus</a> are assigned to the web pages.</p>
                <p>If you chose to include the setting <i>Include similar terms in search</i> by putting a cross, the associated similar terms will be taken into account. (Note: In most cases the number of hits will be increased by selecting this setting.)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Tips</header>
        <section help-key="search-tipps-1">
            <header>You would also like to include similar terms in the search?</header>
            <content>
                <p>You have three possibilities for including similar terms in the search:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Automatically: In the settings for the search options form (<a
                        href="?hkey=search-settings-1">Search/Options</a>)
                        cross the option <i>Include similar terms in search</i>. You can also use these setting on a lasting basis (see <a
                            href="?hkey=myingrid-1">myPortalU</a>).</li>
                    <li>Before conducting a search expand your search term with similar terms by using the 
                            <i><a
                        href="?hkey=ext-search-subject-2">Topic/Thesaurus</a></i>
                        functionality of the <i><a
                            href="?hkey=ext-search-1">Advanced Search</a></i>.</li>
                    <li>After a search you will be offered <i><a
                            href="?hkey=ext-search-subject-5">Similar Terms</a></i> above the search results list, by means of which you can expand your search term. In order to see the similar terms click on <i>Similar Terms: Search for.... </i> or on the plus sign. </li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-tipps-2">
            <header>You would like to limit your search to information about the place you live in?</header>
            <content>
                <p>For this use  <i><a
                        href="?hkey=ext-search-spacial-1">Space</a></i>.You can either call up a search rectangle over the search area desired (<i><a
                    href="?hkey=ext-search-spacial-6">By Map</a></i>)
                    or enter your town or district as a term (<i><a
                        href="?hkey=ext-search-spacial-2">By Geographic Name</a></i>).</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-tipps-3">
            <header>You are only interested in information about your Federal State?</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can select your Federal State via the  <i><a
                        href="?hkey=ext-search-area-1">Search-Area</a></i> of the search. Be aware that information at national level could also be of interest to you. You can set national information in the search area as well as a Federal State. </p>
                <p>You can also have these settings on a lasting basis (see  <a href="?hkey=myingrid-1">myPortalU</a>).</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-tipps-4">
            <header>You have a particular search query that you can’t formulate via the advanced search?</header>
            <content>
                <p>PortalU allows complex search queries to be carried out that go beyond the possibilities of the advanced search (e.g. grouping via bracketing or similarity search etc.). In PortalU’s help read the section <i><a
                    href="?hkey=search-expert-1">Expert Entry</a></i>
                    and put your search term into the search field.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search for Addresses</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-address-1">
            <header>Topic</header>
            <section help-key="ext-search-address-2">
                <header>Search Terms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>In this area you can add one or more search terms to your search in a targeted manner by linking them with one of the following options:</p>
                    <p>
                     <b>all search terms (AND):</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>all</b> the terms entered (standard).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>one of the search terms (OR):</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>at least one</b> of the terms entered.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>the exact search string:</b>a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>exactly </b>the word group entered (in the same sequence, with spaces etc.).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>none of the search terms:</b> a piece of information will only be found if it contains <b>none</b> of the terms entered.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-address-3">
                <header>Search Mode</header>
                <content>
                    <p>In this area you can determine whether your search terms will only be found if they agree with a whole word in the address being searched or whether it is sufficient if only a part of the entire word (substring) in the address agrees with the respective search term.</p>
                    <p>You can further determine whether the search is to be carried out in <i>All Text-Fields</i> of the address (e.g. therefore in the <i>Street</i> field too) or only in the fields <i>Institutions</i>, <i>Persons</i>, <i>Description</i> and <i>Keywords</i>.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-address-4">
            <header>Space</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can restrict the search for an address to a <i>Street</i>, <i>Postal Code</i> or a <i>City</i>. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
		<section help-key="ext-search-address-5">
            <header>Search Area</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can select a region (Federation/Federal States) or a specific information provider. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search for Research Projects</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-research-1">
            <header>Search Terms</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can add one or more terms to your search in a targeted manner by linking them with one of the following options:</p>
                <p>
                    <b>all search terms (AND):</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>all</b> the terms entered (standard).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>one of the search terms (OR):</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>at least one</b> of the terms entered.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>the exact search string:</b>a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>exactly </b>the word group entered (in the same sequence, with spaces etc.).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>none of the search terms:</b> a piece of information will only be found if it contains <b>none</b> of the terms entered.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-research-2">
            <header>Attributs</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can restrict the search for research projects, to the <i>Project Name</i>, the <i>Institutions </i>taking part, the <i>Project Manager</i>, other <i>Participants</i>, the <i>Project Sponsor</i> and the <i>Running Time</i>. </p>
                <p>Please note that, when using these filter possibilities, the search will be exclusively restricted to databases that support a search in the respective attribute. You are therefore restricting the search doing this, considerably so, as the case may be. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced search for Laws</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-law-1">
            <header>Search terms</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can add one or more terms to your search in a targeted manner by linking them with one of the following options:</p>
                <p>
                        <b>all search terms (AND):</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>all</b> the terms entered (standard).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>one of the search terms (OR):</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>at least one</b> of the terms entered.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>the exact search string:</b>a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>exactly </b>the word group entered (in the same sequence, with spaces etc.).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>none of the search terms:</b> a piece of information will only be found if it contains <b>none</b> of the terms entered.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-law-2">
            <header>Thesaurus</header>
            <content>
                  <p>You can add specialist terms to your search via the specialist dictionary. For this you enter any term into the entry field and send a query to the <a href="#ext-search-subject-3">thesaurus</a> ab.</p>
                <p>You then receive a series of  <a
                        href="#ext-search-subject-5">similar terms</a>, which you can add to the search term or by linking them you can further specify your search term.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
      <section help-key="ext-search-law-3">
            <header>Search-Area – Federation/Federal States</header>
            <content>
                  <p>The data on offer in PortalU stems from the authorities and closely associated organisations in the Federation and the Federal States of the Federal Republic of Germany. You can limit the range to the Federation or individual Federal States. Selecting several options is possible.</p>
                <p>The Federation as well as most Federal States have several data providers. These are displayed if you click on the plus sign. Instead of the Federal Republic or a Land it is also possible to select individual providers. In this case it is also possible to select several providers.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
		
	
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
	
	
        <header>Save Query</header>
        <section help-key="search-save-1">
            <header>Save Query</header>
            <content>
                <p>After carrying out a search query the users logged in have the possibility of saving the search term used on a long-term basis (see  <a href="?hkey=myingrid-1">myPortalU</a>) die Möglichkeit, den verwendeten Suchausdruck
                    dauerhaft zu speichern. This takes place via the <i>Save Query </i>function.</p>
                <p>Note: The search queries last used are also accessible without saving for the session in progress via <i><a
                    href="?hkey=search-history-1">Search History</a></i>.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Expert Entry</header>
        <section help-key="search-expert-1">
            <header>Expert Entry</header>
            <content>
                <p>All settings of the advanced search and some further additional special settings can also be entered directly into the search via the search string. As the syntax is very extensive because of the great number of search methods, it is meant for experts in particular.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-2">
            <header>Boolean operators</header>
            <content>
                <p>The individual search terms can be linked via Boolean operators. The following operators are available:</p>
                <p><b>AND</b>: All the words have to be in the document. It is the standard if no operator is given. (Note: instead of AND the symbol &amp;&amp; can be used)<br/> For example: &#8218;water fish&#8217; equates to &#8218;water AND fish&#8217; or &#8218;water &amp;&amp; fish&#8217; </p>
                <p>
                    <b>OR</b>: One of the words has to be in the document. (Note: instead of OR the symbol || can be used) <br/> Example:
                    &#8218;water OR fish&#8217; equates to 
                    &#8218;water || fish&#8217;</p>
                <p>
                    <b>NOT</b>: The word after NOT must not be in the document. (Hint: instead of NOT the symbol ! or the symbol l - can be used)<br/> Example: &#8218;water NOT
                    fish&#8217; (the search is for water but not fish)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-3">
            <header>Grouping (bracketing)</header>
            <content>
                <p>The individual search terms linked by Boolean operators can be optionally grouped by bracketing (round brackets).</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;fish NOT (trout OR perch)&#8217;
                    (all documents are found that contain the term
                    &#8218;fish&#8217; but not the terms  &#8218;trout&#8217; and &#8218;perch&#8217;)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-4">
            <header>Search for word groups</header>
            <content>
                <p>If a string is placed in quotation marks (&#8222;)
                    then the occurrence of the whole string is sought and not the occurrence of the individual terms..</p>
                <p>Example: &#8222;The fish swims in the water&#8220;
                    (Only texts are found that contain exactly this string.)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-5">
            <header>Wild cards</header>
            <content>
                <p>Within a search term it is possible to enter wild cards for one (?) or more (*) optional signs. All terms are then found that match the rest of the search term whereby one or more signs can appear for the wild card. </p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;te?t&#8217; (Not only documents with the term&#8218;text&#8217; but also documents with the term  &#8218;test&#8217; will be found)</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;environment*catalogue&#8217; ((not only documents with the term 
                    &#8218;environment data catalogue&#8217; will be found but also documents with the term   &#8218;environment object catalogue&#8217; )</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-6">
            <header>Search for areas of symbols</header>
            <content>
                <p>It is possible to search for areas of symbols. The areas are collected in square  [] or curved  {} brackets and the bottom and top pieces of information are linked with the operator TO. Square brackets[]
                    signify that the lower and upper value of the area are included in the search. Curved brackets  {}
                    signify that the lower and the upper value of the area are not included in the search.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;[Aller TO Elbe]&#8217; (Documents are sought that contain words that begin with all in the alphabet and end at Elbe. The words 
					&#8218;Aller&#8217; and &#8218;Elbe&#8217; are included in the search area by this.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;{Aller TO Elbe}&#8217; (Documents are sought that contain words starting alphabetically with Aller and ending at Elbe. The words 
					&#8218;Aller&#8217; and &#8218;Elbe&#8217; are not contained in the search area in this.)</p>
				<p>The search area can also be given inside a search word. </p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;te[i TO x]t&#8217; (Documents are searched for that contain, for example, the words &#8218;teilt&#8217;, &#8218;test&#8217; or &#8218;text&#8217;.)</p>
				<p> As an alternative to the operator TO a hyphen - can also be used </p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;te[i - x]t&#8217; (documents are searched for that, for example, contain the words  &#8218;tent&#8217;, &#8218;test&#8217; or &#8218;text&#8217;.)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-7">
            <header>Fuzzy search</header>
            <content>
                <p>Documents are also found via the fuzzy search in which terms with similar spelling are found. The fuzzy search is instigated by attaching a tilde (~) to the search term.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;Corn~&#8217; (documents will be found containing the term&#8218;horn&#8217; for example)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-8">
            <header>Special symbols</header>
            <content>
                <p>The following symbols have a special significance in the PortalU search string (e.g. in the form of operators):</p>
                <p>+ - &amp;&amp; || ! ( ) { } [ ] ^ &quot; ~ * ? : \</p>
                <p>SShould you however use them as simple symbols within a search term then they must be marked as such by the symbol
                    \ (Backslash).</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;\(1\+1\)\:2&#8217; (The expression &#8218;(1+1):2&#8217; is sought)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-9a">
            <header>Search for special document types</header>
            <content>
                <p> In PortalU different document types can be searched for. For this the syntax &#8218;fileformat:value&#8217; is used.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;fileformat:pdf&#8217; (only PDF documents are searched for.)</p>
                <p>The following values are available for the 'fileformat' field in PortalU:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Value</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description </b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>pdf </td>  
					<td> Only PDF documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>rtf  </td>  
					<td> Only RTF documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>msword </td>  
					<td> Only MS Word documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>msexcel  </td>  
					<td>Only MS Excel documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>mspowerpoint </td>  
					<td> Only MS PowerPoint documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                </table>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-9">
            <header>Search for special datatypes</header>
            <content>
                <p>The PortalU full text index is organized in different fields. All fields used in PortalU can be searched individually in targeted fashion. For this the syntax
                    &#8218;field name:value&#8217; is used.</p>
				<p>In searching for a data type the field name is &#8218;datatype&#8217;.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;datatype:law&#8217; (documents are searched for that are arranged under legislation.)</p>
                <p>The following values are available for the <i>datatype</i> field in PortalU:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Value</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description</b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    
					 <tr>
					<td>www</td>  
					<td> Web pages are being sought</td>
					</tr>
					
					<tr>
					<td>default</td>  
					<td> Documents from the <i>environment information </i> area are searched for</td>
					</tr>
										
					<tr>
					<td>research</td>  
					<td> Documents from the <i>research projects </i>area are searched for</td>
					</tr>
					
                    <tr>
					<td>address</td>  
					<td> Documents from the <i>addresses</i> area are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    
                    <tr>
					<td>topics</td>  
					<td> Documents from the <i>environment topics</i> area are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                     <tr>
					<td>service</td>  
					<td> Documents from the <i>service</i> area are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>measure</td>  
					<td> Documents from the <i>measurement values</i> (data) are searched for</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>metadata</td>  
					<td> Metadata are searched for</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>fis</td>  
					<td>Information from the specialist databases is being sought</td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-10">
            <header>Search for a particular environmental topic</header>
            <content>
                <p>The search can be limited to pages associated with one or more environmental topics. For this the syntax &#8218;topic:value&#8217; is used.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;datatype:topics topic:energy&#8217; (documents are searched for that are arranged under the environmental topic <i>Energy</i> eingeordnet wurden.)</p>
				<p> The following values are possible:</p>
				<p> Abfall, Altlasten, Bauen, Boden, Chemikalien, Energie, Forstwirtschaft, Gentechnik, 
					Geologie, Gesundheit, LaermErschuetterung, Landwirtschaft, LuftKlima, 
					NachhaltigeEntwicklung, NaturLandschaft, Strahlung, Tierschutz, Umweltinformation,
					Umweltwirtschaft, Verkehr, Wasser </p>
			</content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-11">
            <header>Search for particular measurement pages (data)</header>
            <content>
                <p>The search can be restricted to the pages, which are associated with measurements in particular environmental areas. For this the syntax&#8218;topic:value&#8217; is used.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;datatype:measure topic:air&#8217; (Documents are searched for that have as contents measurements on the topic <i>Air</i>.)</p>
				<p> The following values are possible:</p>
				<p> radiation, air, water, misc </p>
			</content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-12">
            <header>Search for a particular service</header>
            <content>
                <p>The search can be restricted to the pages, which are associated with a service. For this the syntax&#8218;topic:value&#8217; is used.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;datatype:service topic:press&#8217; (Documents containing press releases are searched for.)</p>
				<p> The following values are possible:</p>
				<p> press, publication, event </p>
			</content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-13">
            <header>Search for a particular metadata class (data)</header>
            <content>
				<p>In searching for a particular metadata class the syntax  &#8218;topic:Wert&#8217; is searched for.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;datatype:metadata metaclass:map&#8217; (metadata of the <i>Geo-Information/Map</i> class are being searched for.)</p>
                <p>The following values are available for the <i>metaclass</i> field in PortalU:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Value</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description</b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>job </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class <i>Organisational Unit / Task</i> are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>map  </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class <i>Geo-Information / Map</i> are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>document </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class <i>Document / Report / Literature</i> are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>geoservice </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class <i>Geo-Service </i>are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>project </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class <i>Enterprise / Project / Program</i> are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>database  </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class <i>Data Pooling / Data Base</i> are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
					<td>service  </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class 'Service / Application / Information System' are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                </table>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-14">
            <header>Stating the spatial reference</header>
            <content>
				<p> The search can be restricted to documents that are associated with a certain spatial reference. The spatial reference can be stated via coordinates or via the area key of the administrative unit.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;areaid: areaid:11000000&#8217; (The search will be restricted to Berlin as administrative unit.)</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;x1:7.52 y1:50.18 x2:10.17 y2:52.73&#8217; (The search is restricted to a selected rectangle.)</p>
                <p>The following fields are available in PortalU for the restriction of the spatial reference:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Field</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description of the Value </b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>areaid </td>  
					<td> Key of the administrative unit (AGS)</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>x1  </td>  
					<td> left</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>x2 </td>  
					<td> right</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>y1 </td>  
					<td> up</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>y2 </td>  
					<td> down</td>
					</tr>
               </table>
			   <p> The coordinates have to be entered as degrees (WGS 84). </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-15">
            <header>Stating the temporal reference</header>
            <content>
				<p> The search can be restricted to documents that are associated with a particular temporal reference.  </p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;t1:2006-01-01 t2:2008-12-31&#8217; (The search is restricted to a selected time interval.)</p>
                <p>The following fields are available for the restriction of the temporal references in PortalU:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Field</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description of the Value </b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>t0 </td>  
					<td>The document was associated with the time point stated</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>t1  </td>  
					<td> The document was associated with a time span that begins with the value stated</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>t2 </td>  
					<td> The document was associated with a time span that ends with the value stated</td>
					</tr>
               </table>
			   <p> The times stated must always be entered in the form YYYY-MM-DD (Y=year, M=month, D=day).  </p>
            </content>
        </section>
<!--					
-->
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Search result list</header>
        <section help-key="search-results-1">
            <header>Search result list</header>
            <content>
                <p>After submitting a search query you will receive the result list. It is broken down into the main result list (left column) and the list with results from broader data sources (right column). You will also be given the possibility of refining your search query via the <a
                    href="?hkey=search-1">Search form</a> and to do another search. For this you can also use the similar terms offered to you.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-results-2">
            <header>Main result list</header>
            <content>
                <p>In the main result list you will be shown the results from the search in the web pages of the connected server as well as in the meta- and specialist information systems in a list weighted according to relevance. </p>
                <p>Instead of the simple weighted list you can also have the results displayed  <a
                    href="?hkey=myingrid-12">grouped</a>
                    according to Federal Republic and Federal States or according to providers or  <a href="?hkey=myingrid-12">sorted</a> according to currentness.</p>
                <p>If the information you have found is a webpage then, as well as a series of pieces of information (e.g. title, description and provider), you will receive a link by means of which you will be led directly to the original page.</p>
                <p>If the information you have found is a meta- or specialist information you will be led via the link to the detailed representation of the specialist information. In the cases, where there is a direct link available to a web page in which the meta- or specialist information is available, then you will be offered this and will be led by this to the original page. In the cases in which there is a map beyond, you will get a ‟show map” link offered by means of which you can open the map in PortalU‘s map viewer.</p>
            </content> 
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-results-3">
            <header>Further data sources</header>
            <content>
                <p>As well as the meta- and specialist information systems incorporated in the main result list, further environment information systems are also interrogated via PortalU. The interfaces of these systems do not allow any incorporation of the search results into the weighted main results list. The search results are therefore shown in a separate list sorted according to data sources. In doing so the data sources are listed in the order of successful responses logged. </p>
                <p>You will be guided further via the links provided either directly to the individual search results or to a search result list in the source system according to the data source. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-results-4">
            <header>Similar terms</header>
            <content>
                <p>PortalU offers you the possibility of expanding your search query by similar terms. For this, the search string entered by you will be analysed by the <a
                        href="http://www.semantic-network.de/"
                        target="_new">Semantic Network Service (SNS)</a> of the Federal Environment Agency (Umweltbundesamt) in Dessau-Rosslau and made available to them.</p>
                <p>If you click on the plus sign  <img border="0" width="9"
                        height="9"
                    src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image018.jpg"/> you will be offered the similar terms for each search entered. You can in turn get these displayed by means of the symbol
                        <img border="0" width="9" height="9"
                    src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image018.jpg"/> By putting a cross next to the individual terms and clicking on the <i>Append to Query</i> button, the similar terms will be added to the associated search term each time such that a document will be found if either the search term or the similar term are contained (OR linking).</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Data Catalogues</header>
        <section help-key="search-catalog-1">
            <header>Hierarchy-Tree</header>
            <content>
                <p>The data catalogues connected and its contents are displayed in a hierarchy-tree, broken down according to Federal Republic/Federal States. In each catalogue navigation can take place by <i>Objects</i> (here "environment information") or <i>Addresses</i>. The details of an entry are represented only when queried, i.e. when clicking on its title, just as in the <a
                    href="?hkey=search-results-2"> main results list</a> in the free search.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-catalog-2">
            <header>Thesaurus-Navigator</header>
            <content>
                <p>The representation of the body of words in the Thesaurus takes place in a tree structure, starting with the top terms in SNS. When a Thesaurus term (descriptor) is selected (clicked), the metadata sets of the catalogues (object- and/or address-iPlugs) available are represented, which have been given keywords with the descriptor selected ,in a ‟result list” located next to the hierarchy tree. The listing of the metadatasets is grouped according to the catalogues in this list. The detailed representation of a metadataset only takes place after a query, i.e. by clicking on its title, just as in the list of the search results in the free search. Switching between “environment information” (<i>Objects</i>) and <i>Addresses </i>takes place in the area of the result list.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Environmental Topics</header>
        <section help-key="search-topics-1">
            <header>Environmental Topics</header>
            <content>
                <p>The information that is provided as <i>Environmental Topics</i> in PortalU are web pages and EDC-metadata objects (Environmental Data Catalogues) which are particularly relevant for a certain topic. You can select the actual topic (such as, for example, water or refuse) of the topic page wished.</p>
                <p>If you have arrived at a topic directly from the start page on the environmental topics, the topic chosen is already pre-loaded and only the topic pages on this topic will be shown in the results list. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-topics-2">
            <header>Topics</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can select the topic you wish to find information about.</p>
                <p>You can carry out multiple selections by holding down the ctrl-key and then clicking on the topics desired. </p>
                <p>If <i>Select All </i>is selected all the topics available will be displayed.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-topics-4">
            <header>Federation/Federal States</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can select which information providers (of the Federation or individual Federal States) you want the information from.</p>
                <p>You can carry out multiple selections by holding down the ctrl-key and then clicking on the Federation or the Federal States desired.v</p>
                <p>If <i>Select All</i> is selcted then the information from all information providers is displayed.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-topics-5">
            <header>Grouping</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can display the results grouped either according to the Federation and Federal States or according to the individual information providers (e.g. Federal Ministry of the Environment). This means that all the information of the Federation or of a German Federal State resp. of a provider will be collected in a group and displayed together.</p>
                <p>If you do not want such a grouping you can select the <i>No </i>setting.</p>
                  </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Service</header>
        <section help-key="search-service-1">
            <header>Service</header>
            <content>
                <p>Under <i>Service </i>all the <i>Press Releases</i>, <i>Publications</i> and <i>Events</i> headings of the Federation and the of the Federal States are collected together.</p>
                <p>From this menu item you reach the corresponding pages of the Federation- and Federal States- authorities.</p>
                <p>If you klick at the PortalU-startside on a link in the servicebox (e.g. <i>Events</i>), the results for the chosen category (e.g. Events) are displayed directly. Here a change in the category Service takes places.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-service-2">
            <header>Categories</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can select certain categories. After clicking on the <i>Show</i> button the pages available on the categories crossed will be displayed for you. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-service-3">
            <header>Federation/Federal States</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can select which information providers (of the Federation or individual Federal States) you want the information from.</p>
                <p>You can carry out multiple selections by holding down the ctrl-key and then clicking on the Federation or the Federal States desired.v</p>
                <p>If <i>Select All</i> is selcted then the information from all information providers is displayed.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-service-4">
            <header>Grouping</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can display the results grouped either according to the Federation and Federal States or according to the individual information providers (e.g. Federal Ministry of the Environment). This means that all the information of the Federation or of a German Federal State resp. of a provider will be collected in a group and displayed together.</p>
                <p>If you do not want such a grouping you can select the <i>No</i> setting.</p>
                  </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Data (Measured Values)</header>
        <section help-key="search-measure-1">
            <header>Environmental Monitoring data</header>
            <content>
                <p>Under the menu item <i>Data</i> the web pages and information systems on measurement data belonging to the Federal Republic and the Federal States will be displayed to you.</p>
                <p>If you have reached the measured data directly from the start page by clicking on the heading <i>Data</i>, the heading has been already pre-selected and the pages available are displayed directly.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-measure-2">
            <header>Categories</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can select which environment medium you want up-to-date readings displayed for. After clicking on the <i>Show</i> button, the pages available with readings for the categories crossed are displayed.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-measure-3">
            <header>Federation/Federal States</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can select which information providers (of the Federation or individual Federal States) you want the information from.</p>
                <p>You can carry out multiple selections by holding down the ctrl-key and then clicking on the Federation or the Federal States desired.v</p>
                <p>If <i>Select All</i> is selcted then the information from all information providers is displayed.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-measure-4">
            <header>Grouping</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can display the results grouped either according to the Federation and Federal States or according to the individual information providers (e.g. Federal Ministry of the Environment). This means that all the information of the Federation or of a German Federal State resp. of a provider will be collected in a group and displayed together.</p>
                <p>If you do not want such a grouping you can select the <i>No</i> setting.</p>
                  </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Almanac</header>
        <section help-key="search-chronicle-1">
            <header>Environmental Almanac</header>
            <content>
                <p>The environmental almanac is a collection of current and historical events which have significantly influenced our environment situation. As well as the basic data, the environmental almanac provides a short description of the events.</p>
                <p>The environmental almanac is made available via the  <a
                        href="http://www.semantic-network.de/"
                        target="_new">Semantic Network Service (SNS)</a> of the Federal Environment Agency (Umweltbundesamt).</p>
                <p>You can search in a targeted manner for events by submitting a search in the environment chronicle via <i>Search Term</i>, <i>Temporal Relation</i> and <i>Event-Type</i> using the <i>Show</i> button.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-chronicle-2">
            <header>Event-Type</header>
            <content>
                <p>The environmental almanc lists different event types. In this area you can choose which types of event you are searching for.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-chronicle-3">
            <header>Temporal Relation</header>
            <content>
                <p>The environment chronicle lists the date for every event upon which it happened. In this area you can give the point in time or the time period in which you are searching for environment-relevant events. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-chronicle-4">
            <header>Search Term</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can enter a search term in this area. Events are searched for containing the search term in the title or in the description.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Maps</header>
        <section help-key="maps-1">
            <header>Maps</header>
            <content>
                <p>In Map viewer you can view maps relevant to the environment. Select a map service from the heading <i>Topics</i> or the heading <i>Federation/Federal States</i> or add an external service. If you have reached Map viewer via a PortalU-search result (<i>Show Map</i>), the corresponding map will be displayed to you immediately.
                   </p>
            </content>
        </section>
            <section help-key="maps-2">
				<header>Accordion Menu </header>
                <content>
                    <p>In the PortalU map viewer available, as well as activated map services, keys and a metadatasearch are provided in an accordion men, which is situated to the left of the map. By clicking on a menu heading the respective menu item will be opened up.</p>
					
                    <p><b>Legend</b></p>
                    <p>In the menu item <i>Legend</i> all the keys available are displayed for the map layers activated under<i>Active Services</i> and which are depicted in the map viewer. The legend description provides information which symbols and/or colours are used for the different information displayed in the map.</p>
                   <p><b>Aktive Services</b></p>
                    <p>All map services, which are found under <i>Active Services</i>, can be activated or de-activated by one click in map viewer. The map services with their layers are represented in a tree structure. </p>
									   
					<p>The individual symbols have the following meaning:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image101.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Moves the selection up</b> : highlighted service or a marked layer is moved up one level. A service or layer can be highlighted by one click with the left mouse button on the name. As regards depiction in the map: layers that are listed further down in the tree structure overlay layers that are listed further down. </p>								
                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image102.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Moves the selection down:</b> A highlighted service or layer is displaced downwards by one level. A service or layer can be highlighted by one click with the left mouse button on the name. When a layer is overlaid by another then this can be made visible by being pushed downwards. The layer that is at the bottom of the list is always depicted as the topmost layer in the map.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image114neu.png"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Removes the selected WMS:</b> A highlighted service or layer is deleted from the ?active services" area. A service can be highlighted by one click with the left mouse button on the name. The removal of single layers is not possible. </p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="20" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image106.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>  	Active Services</b> : The folder symbol is used to display the map services. In the individual folders are to be found the corresponding layers of a service. With one click (left mouse button) on the folder symbol you can move the service, remove it or alter its transparency.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image107.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Active Services</b>: This symbol is used to display a layer. With one click (left mouse button) on the symbol you can move the service, zoom in to the level of the service or call up information.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="17" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image108.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>  	(De)activate this service </b>: If the left check box is ticked for a service or a layer, the service or the layer in the map is activated and depicted in the map if the corresponding zoom level (pre-defined standard of the layer) is set. If the map section depicted is outside the zoom level of the layer then the layer is not displayed in the map and the layer title is depicted in grey. If the tick for a service is removed then all the layers of the service are de-activated.  </p>

					<p> <img border="0" width="18" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image104.jpg"
                        alt="*"/>  <b> 	Show Metadata: </b> Further information (metadata) about a service and/or a layer is displayed for Web Map Services, which are entered below Topics or Federation/Ferderal States. The information, which originate from the particular GetCapabilities-URL, are readout from the data base of the PortalU - Map viewer. If in the GetCapabilities-URL specific data as e.g. to the organisation or address are lacking, some fields can not be filled.</p>

					<p><b>Topics</b></p>
                    <p>Under topics you will find various map services of the Federation and Federal States sorted according to environment topics, which can be loaded into the PortalU map viewer.</p>
                   					   
					<p>The symbols used have the following meaning:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="17" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image109.jpg"
                        alt="*"/>   	The folder symbol is used for displaying the individual environment topics. In the folder you will find the corresponding map services.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="22"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image111.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding service will be added to the active services and the map section depicted by the service will be zoomed in on in the map.  </p>
 					<p>Note: If the service contains fewer than 5 layers all the layers will be activated directly in the map as well. Should the service contain more than 5 layers then the layers will not be automatically activated. </p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image104.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> <b>  	Show metadata:  </b> Further information (metadata) about a service and/or a layer is displayed for Web Map Services, which are entered below Topics or Federation/Ferderal States. The information, which originate from the particular GetCapabilities-URL, are readout from the data base of the PortalU - Map viewer. If in the GetCapabilities-URL specific data as e.g. to the organisation or address are lacking, some fields can not be filled. </p>

                    <p><b>Federation /Federal States</b></p>
                    <p>Under <i>Federation /Federal States</i> you will find environmentally-relevant map services of different institutions and organisations of the Federation and the Federal States sorted on a regional basis (according to Federation and Federal States).</p>
                    
					<p>The meaning of the individual symbols is described under the <i>Topics</i> menu item (see above).</p>
						
                    <p><b>Metadatasearch</b></p>
                    <p>In <i>Metadatasearch</i> you can search for map services of the Federation and Federal States which are incorporated in the PortalU map viewer. Enter a search term for this and click on <i>OK</i>. </p>
                    			
					
					<p>In the search results list the following symbols are used:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="15" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image110.jpg"
                        alt="*"/>   	With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding layer is added to the active services. </p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="22"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image111.jpg"
                        alt="*"/>   	With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding layer is added to the active services and the map section described by the layer is zoomed in on. </p>
					<p> With one click on the name of the service and/or of the layer further information on the service and/or layer is displayed.	</p>
                 </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="maps-3">
                <header>Save Map</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you have registered with your account under myPortalU, you can 
					save your settings under Active Services. For this click on the link Save Map above Legend. 
					Below the map viewer appeares a dialogue field offering the possibility to save the actual 
					map view under a user-defined name. A permanent URL ist defined, which can be used later.</p>
               	
      				
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="maps-4">
                <header>Tool Bar</header>
                <content>
                    <p>Via the tool bar you can carry out different actions directly or by clicking in the map.</p>
                   <p> <img border="0" width="294" height="46"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image207.jpg"
                        alt="*"/></p>			
                    <p>
                        <b>Add External Services </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image024.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By means of this button you can add any GetCapabilities-URL (external service). The service is added to the active services and depicted in the map viewer with the <i>Add WMS</i> button. </p>
					<p> Here you can select (check box) whether you want to activate the layer of the service straight away and whether you want to zoom in to the map section of the service directly. </p>
                    <p><b>Show Data</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image026.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> Which information is displayed depends on for which layer under <i>Active Services </i>the right check box <i>Info Query in Map</i> has been activated (see above). At present not all services support this function.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Display Coordinates </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image027.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By means of this button point coordinates can be called up in the map. The position of the mouse is displayed in geographical coordinates under the map. The coordinates of the last click in the map are also displayed. .</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Zoom in </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image031.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With this button you can zoom in on the map. You can draw up a map section by holding down the left mouse button to draw up a rectangle. The map is centered on this section and correspondingly enlarged.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Zoom out </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image032.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With one click on this button the map is reduced by a half.</p>
                    <p>
                    <b>Move Map</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image033.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> Via this button the map can be dragged. To drag: With the left mouse button click on a point in the map, hold the button down and pull the mouse over the map. After this process, the point on the map on which you clicked is then found to be located where you let go of the left mouse button. </p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Back</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image034.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking on this button, the map section, which was displayed before the last action, is restored.</p>
                    <p>The action can be carried out several times in succession.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Forward</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image035.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> If you have gone back to a map section, which lies one or more actions back, using the <i>Back</i> button, you can leaf forward again through the actions you performed after that using the <i>Forward</i> button. The action can be performed as often as the<i>Back</i> action was performed previously.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Show Original Map</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image037.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking this button the zoom area of the original map is restored.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Print</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image039.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking on this button a PDF document of the map is produced with or without a key. You can choose the alignment of the map and also add a title and a commentary to the map. You can print the document via the usual PDF functionality or save it.</p>
						
						
                </content>
            </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>News</header>
        <section help-key="rss-news-1">
            <header>News</header>
            <content>
                <p>Under <i>News</i>
				are listed current releases on the subject of the environment from the federal and regional authorities. Here the latest report is always on top. Each time only the title and a short description of the report are displayed. By clicking on the report you will be taken to the original report.</p>
                <p>Older reports, which are no longer displayed on the start page, are stored in the report archive. You can look at these reports by clicking on the <i>Other News</i> link.</p>
                <p>Note: If necessary, you can still find reports, which are so old that they can no longer be found in the report archive, on the original servers of the respective federal or regional authorities. To do this click on <a
                        href="?hkey=search-service-1">Service / News-Bulletins</a>.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>PortalU informs</header>
        <section help-key="ingrid-inform-1">
            <header>PortalU informs</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can find reports, which are provided by the operator of PortalU, the <a href="http://www.kst.portalu.de/"
                        target="_new">Coordination Center PortalU</a>.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>My PortalU</header>
        <section help-key="myingrid-1">
            <header>My PortalU</header>
            <content>
                <p>PortalU offers you the possibility of putting your own settings in place on lasting basis. Using these you can:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Adapt the start page to your requirements</li>
                    <li>Personalise the search</li>
                </ul>
                <p>To do this you must register and receive a user name and a password. Registration is free. Your details will not be passed on and are only used in anonymised form for statistical purposes. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-2">
            <header>Login</header>
            <content>
                <p>If you already have a user name and a password you can enter them here and click on <i>Sign-on</i>.</p>
            </content>
            <section help-key="myingrid-3">
                <header>New User</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you do not yet have a user name and password then click on the <i>New User</i> link. This will take you to the <i>Login </i>form. </p>
                    <p>Please fill out the form. The detail fields with a star* are mandatory and must be filled in. All other details are voluntary.</p>
                    <p>All details are handled in strict confidence and are only used for anonymised statistical evaluation.</p>
                    <p>If you would always like to receive the latest news from the PortalU arena then order the <a
                        href="?hkey=ingrid-newsletter-1">PortalU Newsletter</a>, by putting a cross against <i>I want to subscribe to the newsletter</i> at the end of the contact form (Note: you can unsubscribe at any time).</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-4">
                <header>Forgotten password?</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you have forgotten your password, click on the <i>Password forgotten?</i> link. You will then be taken to the corresponding form in which you can enter your e-mail address. After submitting you will be sent your user name and password by return.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-5">
                <header>Automatic Login</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you would always like to use your personal settings you can select the <i>Automatic Login</i> option. Then you will not have to enter your username and password every time to access the site. (Note: this operation functions only if you have given your internet browser permission to use cookies).</p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-6">
            <header>Your personal PortalU start page</header>
            <content>
                <p>This link leads you to your personal start page as set up by you in the personalisation function.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-7">
            <header>Edit User Profile</header>
            <content>
                <p>This link takes you to the form with your details thus far. If your details have changed, this is where you can update with these changes.</p>
                <p>The data fields with a star * are mandatory and have to be filled in. All other details are voluntary.</p>
                <p>All details are handled in strict confidence and are only used for anonymised statistical evaluation.</p>
                <p>If you would always like to receive the latest news from the PortalU arena then order the <a
                        href="?hkey=ingrid-newsletter-1">PortalU Newsletter</a>, by putting a cross against <i>I would like to subscribe to the newsletter</i> at the end of the form (Note: you can unsubscribe at any time).</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-8">
            <header>Personalisation</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can set the following settings according to your wishes.</p>
            </content>
            <section help-key="myingrid-9">
                <header>Personalisation of the PortalU Main-Page</header>
                <content>
                    <p>In this area you can set which contents are to be displayed in which order on your personal start page. For this you set the contents of lines 1 to 3 in the main column (on the left) of the start page via the dropdown list. If you do not set your contents at all (empty entry in the dropdown list) this is also not displayed.</p>
                    <p>You can follow the same procedure for the margin column (narrower margin on the right side) of the start page.</p>
						
 				 <p>The determinations are not saved permanently as presetting. After click on <i>Logout</i> you return to the startpage of PortalU with its own presettings.</p>
						
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-10">
                <header>Filter for states or information providers</header>
                <content>
                    <p>In this area you can set whether the information displayed for you is to be restricted to only the Federal Republic and/or individual Federal States (e.g. Federal Republic and Hessen) or is to be restricted to individual information providers (e.g. Federal Ministry of the Environment).</p>
                    <p>The settings relate to the search as well as to the topics pages, readings and service areas.</p>
                    <p>The settings are saved permanently as preset settings. However, you can overwrite them again temporarily via the settings possibilities in the abovementioned areas (thus, for example, for individual searches).</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-11">
                <header>Filter for Types and Data Sources</header>
                <content>
                    <p>As well as the usual web servers, metadata and specialist data systems are also connected to PortalU. You can now select whether you want to search in all data sources (standard) or whether you would like to restrict your search in a targeted manner to one or several types of data sources.</p>
                    <p>If you limit yourself to metadata then you will continue to have the possibility of selecting the classes of metadata you would like to search. The following classes are available to you:</p>
                    <ul>

                        <li>Organisational Unit / Task</li>
						<li>Geo-Information / Map</li>
						<li>Document / Report / Literature</li>
						<li>Geo-Service</li>
                        <li>Enterprise / Project / Program</li>
						<li>Data Pooling / Data Base</li>
						<li>Service / Application / Information System </li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>The settings made will be effective on a lasting basis as preset settings. You can however overwrite them via temporary settings for individual searches. </p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-12">
                <header>Sorting and grouping of search results</header>
                <content>
                    <p>You can display your search results either according to ranking (relevance of the page found with regard to your search term) or according to actuality (the latest pages are shown first).</p>
                    <p>Grouping means that all search results of a page are collected in groups. Depending on the setting, all the search results for the Federation or of a Federal State are collected together or those of all providers or domains.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Include similar terms in the search </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>PortalU not only performs the usual indexing of the pages found on search engines but gets the page contents analysed by the n <a
                            href="http://www.semantic-network.de/"
                            target="_new">Semantic Network Service (SNS)</a> of the Federal Environment Agency (Umweltbundesamt). As a result of this analysis, appropriate technical terms from the <a
                        href="?hkey=ext-search-subject-4#ext-search-subject-4">Environment-Thesaurus</a>
                        are assigned to the web pages.</p>
                    <p>If you select the setting <i>Include similar terms in search</i> by putting a cross then these keywords will be taken account of in the search. (Note: one should assume that selecting this setting increases the number of hits.)</p>
                    <p>The settings will be effective on a lasting basis as preset settings for the display of the search result list, but can be overwritten via settings in <i>Search</i> for individual searches. </p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-13">
            <header>Logout</header>
            <content>
                <p>You leave the personalised area via <i>LOGOUT</i> and return to the start page of PortalU with its standard preset settings.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Newsletter</header>
        <section help-key="ingrid-newsletter-1">
            <header>Newsletter</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can be informed about innovations and current developments in the PortalU arena via our e-mail newsletter. Receiving the newsletter is free of charge. Your e-mail address will not be passed on or used for any other purpose apart from sending the newsletter.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ingrid-newsletter-2">
            <header>Registration for new readers</header>
            <content>
                <p>Please fill in the fields of the registraton form and submit the details. All fields marked with a star * are mandatory.</p>
                <p>You will then receive the PortalU newsletter from the next issue onwards.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ingrid-newsletter-3">
            <header>Unsubscribe newsletter</header>
            <content>
                <p>If you are no longer interested in the PortalU newsletter, then please enter your e-mail address in the form and send. You will then receive no further PortalU newsletters.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
</help>
