<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="ingrid-portal-help.xsl" ?>
<help>
    <chapter>
        <header>General Help for the GS Soil Portal</header>
        <section help-key="index">
            <header>Help for GS Soil Portal</header>
            <content>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ingrid-inform-1">About GS Soil Portal</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-1">Search</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-service-1">Publication</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=maps-1">Maps</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=rss-news-1">News</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=myingrid-1">myGS Soil</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>About GS Soil Portal</header>
        <section help-key="ingrid-inform-1">
            <header>Concept and tasking of GS Soil Portal</header>
            <content>
                <p>Co-funded by the community programme eContentplus GS Soil aims at establishing 
				a Best Practice Network dealing with a cluster of the data themes listed in the Annexes I to III of the 
				<a target="_blank" href="http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=OJ:L:2007:108:0001:0014:EN:PDF">INSPIRE Directive (2007/2/EC)</a> 
				and focused on soil related issues.</p> 
				<p>The establishment of the soil thematic strategy and the new transboundary EU approach for protected sites management has 
				enforced the link between soil conservation and best practice use and geo-information. This has generated the need for 
				interoperable, accessible and harmonised datasets for the EU. The link is also addressed by the INSPIRE Directive which 
				pursues an EU Spatial Data Infrastructure to support environmental policies.</p>
				<p>The GS Soil Network aims, through 
				state-of-the-art methodologies and best practice examples, to improve harmonisation of national datasets and make them more 
				accessible and exploitable within Europe. Therefore, the consortium contributes to the INSPIRE implementation with specific 
				reference to a cluster of data themes on nature conservation (as per the INSPIRE Annexes). Within the INSPIRE directive the 
				theme soil is explicitly addressed as an individual theme (Annex III) and besides that soil related environmental, agricultural 
				and forestry aspects are also addressed in Annex II and III. According to this, the thematic focus of GS Soil is set on soil as 
				an important parameter according to climate, land use, geology and geomorphology. At the same time soils are the basis for food 
				production and consumer health, for the ecological and economical balance and for many other important bases of life.</p>
				<p>Considering the INSPIRE Annexes, the following soil and soil related themes will be considered:</p> 
				<ul>
					<li>Basic soil describing information including depth, texture, structure and organic material as described in Annex III theme "Soil",</li>
					<li>Information about soil monitoring facilities and long term observations as part of the Annex III theme "Environmental Monitoring Facilities",</li>
					<li>Information about the soil related aspects of Annex III theme "Natural Risk Zones" as e.g. landslides, soil erosion, soil compaction, soil organic carbon decline, salinization, acidification and soil biodiversity loss, </li>
					<li>Soil related information of the INSPIRE Annex III theme "Human Health and Safety" and </li>
					<li>Soils as primary site factor to identify protected land as part of the INSPIRE Annex I theme "Protected Sites" (e.g. peat land, extrazonal sites)</li>
				</ul>
				<p>The main objective of the GS Soil Network is to: <br /> 
				<ul>
					<li>involve new stakeholders; </li>
					<li>share data and best practices; </li>
					<li>Improve and stimulate exploitation and </li>
					<li>the re-use of information on nature conservation.</li>
				</ul>
				</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-2">
            <header>GS Soil Portal operators</header>
            <content>
                <p> As expected result from the project GS Soil the GS Soil Portal was set up. The GS Soil Portal provides access to all project
				soil data. GS Soil Portal is maintained from technical and contents point of view by Coordination Center PortalU in the 
				Lower Saxony ministry for environment and climate protection in Hanover.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-3">
            <header>Function overview</header>
            <content>
                <p>
                    <b>Search:</b> Central function of the Portal is the <a href="help.psml?hkey=search-1">Search</a>,
                    with the help of which web pages and data base entries can be searched via a customary full text search (<a
                        href="help.psml?hkey=search-1">Simple search</a>),but can also be searched using a differentiated specialist 
						vocabulary  (<a href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-1">Advanced Search</a>). </p>
                <p>
                    <b>Publication:</b> Here you can find current publications from the soil field.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>Maps</b>: A maps viewer offers the possibility of entering spatial references for the search via interactive maps 
					or else to display digitale maps from the search results list directly in GS Soil Portal.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>News</b>: Current reports are displayed directly from GS Soil News feed.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-4">
            <header>Information sources in GS Soil Portal</header>
            <content>
                <p>GS Soil Portal is a convenient and user-friendly portal for soil and soil related information in the internet. In contrast to most
				portals and search engines, GS Soil Portal gathers not only web pages, text documents and other internet formats but can also 
				access databases and specialist information systems, even when these are not online. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-5">
            <header>Conditions for the use and participation in GS Soil Portal</header>
            <content>
                <p>The circle of data providers in GS Soil Portal restricts itself mainly to GS Soil Network in Europe, but is being continually expanded. If your organisation would likewise like to make 
				soil relevant information available, please contact the <a
                        href="http://www.kst.portalu.de/"
                        target="_new">Coordination Center PortalU</a>.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="about-6">
            <header>InGrid &#8211; the software behind GS Soil Portal</header>
            <content>
                <p>The InGrid software package was developed to realise PortalU the central environmental Information portal for Germany. 
				InGrid is positioned on modular and flexible system architecture based on licence-free open source products. This way it 
				becomes possible to adapt the technical structure of the environment information net to changing organisational specifications. 
				Thus, if needed, regional environment portals, e.g. for individual German Federal States or Local Authorities can be created 
				with minimal technical expense. Thanks to OpenSource the follow up use of the software is license free and free of cost for 
				partners of the VwV UDK/GEIN.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Search</header>
		<section help-key="search-3">
			<header>Quick Start guide to the search</header>
			<content>
				<p>Via the GS Soil Portal you can search for different types of data sources:</p>
				<ul>
						<li>Metadata</li>
						<li>Web pages</li>
						<li>Publications</li>
				</ul>
				<p>For a quick overview about the different data, please enter for</p>
				<ul>
				<p>Metadata: <b>datatype:metadata</b>,</p>
				<p>Web pages: <b>datatype:www</b> and </p>
				<p>Publications: <b>datatype:service</b></p>
				</ul>
				<p>as search query. With those queries you receive all entries from those three data types.</p>
				<p>If you want to specify your search query, please use the different options of the <a href="?hkey=ext-search-1">Advanced search</a>.</p>
			</content>
		</section>
        <section help-key="search-1">
            <header>Simple search</header>
            <content>
                <p>When you use the search function you can enter one or more search terms. Those pages that contain all search terms will be found.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-2">
            <header>Further topics for the search</header>
            <content>
                <p>In addition to the simple search you can further refine your search. Read the following topics on this:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=ext-search-1">Advanced search</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-history-1">History </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-settings-1">Options </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-tipps-1">Tips &amp; Tricks</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-save-1">Save Query</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-expert-1">Expert entry </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-results-1">Search result list </a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="?hkey=search-catalog-2">Thesaurus browser </a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-1">
            <header>Advanced search</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can refine your search for soil information via the <i>Advanced Search</i> option.</p>
                <p>In principle, a search term is composed from individual search terms, which are connected by the operators (AND, OR, NOT). You can read about how you can enter these operators manually in the chapter <a href="help.psml?hkey=search-expert-1">Expert entry </a>.</p>
                <p>The <i>Advanced Search</i> offers you the possibility of constructing your search term using a wizard.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-2">
            <header>Areas for specifying the search</header>
            <content>
                <p>The so-called search area embraces all web pages, documents etc. which are captured by a search query. The following areas are available to you to expand or restrict the search area:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <a href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-subject-1">Topic</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-spacial-1">Space</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-time-1">Time</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-area-1">Search-Area</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced: Topic</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-subject-1">
            <header>Search terms</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can add well directed one or several search terms to your search term by linking it with one of the following options:</p>
                <p>
                    <b>all search terms (AND):</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>all</b> the terms entered (standard).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>one of the search terms (OR):</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>at least one</b> of the terms entered.</p>
                <p>
                    <b>the exact search string:</b> a piece of information will be found if it contains <b>exactly </b>the word group 
					entered (in the same sequence, with spaces etc.).</p>
                <p>
                    <b>none of the search terms (NOT):</b> a piece of information will only be found if it contains <b>none</b> of the terms entered.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-subject-2">
            <header>Thesaurus (Specialist Dictionary)</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can add specialist terms to your search term via the specialist dictionary. To do this you put any term into the entry field and send a query to the <a href="#ext-search-subject-3">Thesaurus</a>.</p>
                <p>You will then receive a series of <a href="#ext-search-subject-5">similar terms</a>,which you can add to the search term. You can further specify your search term by clicking on a similar term.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-subject-4">
			
                <header>What is a Thesaurus?</header>
                <content>
                    <p>Like a dictionary, a thesaurus consists of specialist terms on a certain subject area. In addition to the correct spelling, 
					a thesaurus also contains information whether and how a term can be generalised (superordinate terms), specialised 
					(subordinate terms) or expressed in another way (synonyms). Thesauri are used, for example, for indexing keywords and 
					finding documents. </p>
                    <p>GS Soil Portal uses the GEneral Multilingual Environmental Thesaurus 
					(<a href="http://www.eionet.europa.eu/gemet" target="SNS">GEMET</a>). GEMET is a thesaurus for the 
					classification of environmental resources that has been developed by the European Environment Agency (EEA) and the 
					European Topic Centre on Catalogue of Data Sources (ETCCDS) together with international experts. It contains 
					6.562 terms which have been arranged in a classification scheme and the terms have been translated into 31 languages.</p>  
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-subject-5">
                <header>Similar Terms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>After your search terms are analysed by the semantic service, similar terms are displayed from the thesaurus. You can highlight 
					one or more of these terms and adopt them in your search term (<i>Add to Query</i>).</p>
                    <p>However, you also have the possibility of further specifying a <i>similar term</i> by clicking on the respective term. It will then be shown as a  <a href="#_Thesaurus-Schlagwort">thesaurus keyword</a>. In addition, the associated  
						<a href="#_Oberbegriffe">superordinate</a>,
						<a href="#_Unterbegriffe">subordinate</a> and 
						<a href="#_Verwandte_Begriffe">related terms</a>
                        will be displayed as well as the <a href="#_Synonyme">synonyms</a>.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-subject-6">
                <header>Thesaurus Keyword</header>
                <content>
                    <p>This is the thesaurus keyword currently set. You can adopt it into your search term by crossing it and clicking on the <i>Add to Query</i> button</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-subject-7">
                <header>Superordinate Terms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>A superordinate term is a term that generalises a thesaurus keyword. GEMET provides the possibility of a thesaurus term having several superordinate terms.</p>
                    <p>You can add the superordinate term(s) to your search term by crossing it and clicking on the <i>Add to Query</i> button.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-subject-8">
                <header>Subordinate Terms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>A subordinate term is a term that makes a thesaurus keyword more specific. A thesaurus term can possess as many subordinate terms as desired.</p>
                    <p>You can add one or more subordinate terms to your search term by crossing them and clicking on <i>Add to Query</i> button.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-subject-9">
                <header>Related Terms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>A related term is a thesaurus term that is connected with the thesaurus keyword, but is neither a super nor a subordinate term. A thesaurus term can possess any number of related terms.</p>
                    <p>You can add one or more related terms to your search term by crossing them and clicking on the <i>Add to Query</i>.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-subject-10">
                <header>Synonyms</header>
                <content>
                    <p>A synonym is an alternative expression, but one with the same meaning for the thesaurus keyword.</p>
                    <p>Sometimes a synonym consists of two or several thesaurus terms. In this case, the synonym is not to be understood as an alternative expression for a single thesaurus term but as a synonym for the combined term.</p>
                    <p>You can add one or more synonyms to your search term by crossing them and clicking <i>Add to Query</i> button.</p>
                    <p>If you click on the synonym term then you will reach the thesaurus terms behind. You can also adopt these in your search expresssion.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search: Space</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-1">
            <header>Space</header>
            <content>
                <p>Via the <a href="#ext-search-spacial-3">gazetteer</a> GS Soil Portal analyses for every web page, which is made available by 
					GS Soil Portal, the according spatial reference. This spatial reference is used in GS Soil Portal whithin the framework 
					of the area search. Therefore, the area search is not, as in most other search engines, a full text search for spatial terms.</p>
					<p>In the connected databasees the area search takes place by browsing the area attributes entered there.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-2">
            <header>Restricting area <i>By Geographic Name</i></header>
            <content>
                <p>You can add geographical terms in a targeted way to your search term via conceptual area restriction. To do this you enter 
				any term into the entry field and send a query to the  <a href="#ext-search-spacial-3">Gazetteer</a> 
				(Button <i>Look up Geographic Names</i>). Thereby a query to the gazetteer is started.</p> 
					<p>Then you receive a listing of geographical names, which you can add to the <i>search term</i>. If you want further to 
					specify your search term, just click one of the geographic names in the result list. Now a list appears with further geographic 
					names which feature a position relation to the originally search result.</p>
            </content>
            <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-3">
                <header>What is a gazatteer?</header>
                <content>
                    <p>Just like the place index of an atlas, the gazetteer depicts the names of communities, rivers, mountains, landscapes 
					and other geographical objects in Europe. In so doing, the gazetteer gives the exact spelling as well as the geographical 
					position (coordinates) of a place.</p>
                    <p>The gazetteer is made available via the semantic service integrated in the GS Soil Portal.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
			<section help-key="ext-search-spacial-4">
                <header>Pocedure in GS Soil Portal</header>
                <content>
                    <p>The search term that you have sent off via the <i>Search geographical names</i> button is analysed by the semantic service 
					and you receive a series of geographical names by return. You can now add a cross to these and add them to your search term. 
					The geographical names are used to search for an area in the area information of the web pages and the data bases. </p>
                    <p>If you want to further refine your area search terms then you can look at the positional relationships by clicking once 
					on the respective term.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-5">
                <header>Positional relationships</header>
                <content>
                    <p>After clicking on a geographical name, the positional relationships to this name are displayed. The positional 
					relationships are a measure for the spatial relevance between two geographical objects. By selecting (clicking on) 
					positionally relevant geographical names you can further concretise the spatial reference desired.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
			<section help-key="ext-search-spacial-11">
                <header>Description of gazetteer feature classes</header>
                <content>
					<p>The GS Soil gazetteer based on <a href="http://www.geonames.org/">GeoNames</a>. In the following the core feature classes from GeoNames are described. 
					If you are interessted in the complete list of feature classes please visite the <a href="http://www.geonames.org/statistics/germany.html">feature statistic</a> of GeoNames.</p>
                    <p><b>Administrative Boundary Features (country, state, region,...)</b></p>
					<p>A.ADM4: fourth-order administrative division </p>	
					<ul><p>A subdivision of a fourth-order administrative division.</p></ul>
					<p>A.ADMD: administrative division</p>	
					<ul><p>An administrative division of a country, undifferentiated as to administrative level.</p></ul>
					<p>A.ADM3: third-order administrative division</p>
					<ul><p>A subdivision of a third-order administrative division.</p></ul>
					<p>A.ADM2: second-order administrative division</p>	
					<ul><p>A subdivision of a second-order administrative division.</p></ul>
					<p>A.ADM1: first-order administrative division</p>	
					<ul><p>A primary administrative division of a country, such as a state in Germany.</p></ul>
					<p>A.PCLI: independent political entity</p>
					
					<p><b>Populated Place Features (city, village,...)</b></p>
					<p>P.PPL: populated place</p>	
					<ul><p>A city, town, village, or other agglomeration of buildings where people live and work.</p></ul>
					<p>P.PPLA4: seat of a fourth-order administrative division</p>	
					<p>P.PPLX: section of populated place</p>
					<p>P.PPLL: populated locality</p>
					<ul><p>An area similar to a locality but with a small group of dwellings or other buildings.</p></ul>
					<p>P.PPLA2: seat of a second-order administrative division</p>
					<p>P.PPLQ: abandoned populated place</p>	
					<p>P.PPLA: seat of a first-order administrative division</p>
					<ul><p>Seat of a first-order administrative division (PPLC takes precedence over PPLA).</p></ul>
					<p>P.PPLF: farm village</p>
					<ul><p>A populated place where the population is largely engaged in agricultural activities.</p></ul>
					<p>P.PPLA3: seat of a third-order administrative division</p>	
					<p>P.PPLS: populated places</p>
					<ul><p>Cities, towns, villages, or other agglomerations of buildings where people live and work.</p></ul>
					<p>P.PPLC: capital of a political entity</p>
					<p>P.PPLG: seat of government of a political entity</p>
					
					<p><b>Area Features (parks,area, ...)</b></p>
					<p>L.AREA: area</p>	
					<ul><p>A tract of land without homogeneous character or boundaries.</p></ul>
					<p>L.RGN: region</p>	
					<ul><p>An area distinguished by one or more observable physical or cultural characteristics.</p></ul>
					
					<p><b>Road / Railroad Features (road, railroad )</b></p>
					<p>R.RD: road</p>	
					<p>R.ST: street</p>
					<p>R.RR: railroad</p>
					
					<p><b>Spot Features (spot, building, farm)</b></p>
					<p>H.STM: stream </p>	
					<p>H.LK: lake</p>
					<p>H.PND: pond</p>	
					<p>H.HBR: harbor(s)</p>
					
					<p><b>Road / Railroad Features (road, railroad )</b></p>
					<p>S.HTL: hotel</p>	
					<p>S.BLDG: building(s)</p>
					<p>S.RSTN: railroad station</p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-6">
            <header>Restricting area <i>By Map</i></header>
            <content>
                <p>The GS Soil search can be restricted as to area not only via terms but also by selecting a map section (bounding box). 
				When you have defined a suitable bounding box, a targeted search runs over the web provision made available via GS Soil 
				Portal for area terms (such as, for example, towns, mountains etc.) that are found in the map section. In the databases 
				available via GS Soil Portal, the map section (search rectangle) is searched for directly.</p>
                <p>For orientation and specifiation of a map section you can use the background maps service (Web Map Service) of GS Soil 
				Portal or use external map services.</p>
				<p>In the GS Soil map viewer map services, legends and metadata search are sorted in different tabs, 
				which are situated to the left of the map. By clicking on a tab the respective menu item will be opened.</p>
            </content>
            <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-7">
				<header>Tabs</header>
                <content>
                    <p>In the GS Soil map viewer map services, legends, metadata search and WFS download are sorted in 
					different tabs, which are situated to the left of the map. By clicking on a tab the respective menu item will be opened.</p>
					<p><img border="0" width="191" height="145"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image201.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>
                    <p><b>Legend</b></p>
                    <p>In the menu item <i>Legend</i> all available legends of the map layers are depicted, which are activated under 
					<i>Active Services</i> and are depicted as maps in the viewer. The legend gives information about which symbols 
					and/or colours are used to display the different information in the map.</p>
                   <p><b>Active Services</b></p>
                    <p>All map services found under <i>Active Services</i> can be activated or de-activated by one click in map viewer. 
					The map services with their layers are depicted in a tree structure.</p>
					<p><img border="0" width="306" height="94"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image202.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>					   
					<p>The single symbols have the following meaning:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image101.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Moves the section up:</b> A highlighted service and/or a highlighted layer is pushed upwards by one level. 
						A service or layer can be highlighted by clicking with the left mouse button on the name. For depiction in the map the 
						following applies: layers, which are listed further down in the tree structure, overlie layers that are listed further 
						at the top.</p>								
                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16" src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image102.jpg" alt="*"/>
						<b>Moves the section down:</b> A highlighted service and/or a highlighted layer is displaced downwards by one level. 
						A service or a layer can be highlighted by clicking with the left mouse button on the name. If one layer is overlaid 
						by another one then this can be rendered visible by displacing downwards. The layer, which is at the bottom end of the 
						list, is always depicted as the uppermost layer in the map.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="17" src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image114.jpg" alt="*"/>
						<b>Remove the selected WMS:</b> A highlighted service is deleted from the <i>Active Services</i> area. A service can 
						be highlighted by clicking with the left mouse button on the name. It is not possible to remove individual layers.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="20" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image106.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Active services:</b> The folder symbol is used to display the map services. The corresponding layers 
						of a service are to be found in the individual folders. You can drag, remove the service or alter its transparency 
						with one click (left mouse button) on the folder symbol.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image107.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> This symbol is used to display one <b>layer</b>. You can drag the service, zoom onto the layer of the 
						service or call up information with one click (left mouse key) on the symbol.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="17" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image108.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Toggles the visibility of the service:</b> If the check box for a service or a layer is ticked 
						then the service or layer in the map is activated and shown in the map if the corresponding degree of zoom 
						(pre-defined standard for the layer) is set. Furthermore corresponding layer information can be summoned up 
						in the map via the <i>Query</i> (toolbar) button If the map section represented is outside the zoom level of the 
						layer then the layer in the map is not displayed and the layer title is represented in grey. If a service is 
						ticked then all the layers of the service are activated. If the tick is removed from a service then all the 
						layers of the service are de-activated.</p>
          
					<p> <img border="0" width="18" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image104.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Show metadata:</b> Further information (metadata) about a service and/or a layer is displayed for 
						Web Map Services. The information, which originate from the particular GetCapabilities-URL, are readout from the 
						data base of map viewer. If in the GetCapabilities-URL specific data as e.g. to the organisation or address are lacking, some fields can not be filled.</p>

					<p><b>Topics</b></p>
                    <p>Under topics you will find different map services from data provider sorted according to soil topics and which can be 
					loaded into the map viewer.</p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="304" height="203"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image203.jpg"				   
					     alt="*"/> </p> 
					   
					<p>The single symbols have the following meaning:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="17" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image109.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> The folder symbol is used for displaying different soil topics. In the folder you find the corresponding map services.</p>
 
                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="22"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image111.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add WMS to the active services and zoom in:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the 
						corresponding service is added to the active services and, in the map, the map section described by the service is 
						zoomed in. Here the following also applies: if the service contains less than 11 layers, all layers will be also 
						activated directly in the map. If the service contains more than 10 layers, the layers are not automatically activated 
						to keep the load time low.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image104.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Show metadata:</b> Further information (metadata) about a service and/or a layer is displayed for 
						Web Map Services. The information, which originate from the particular GetCapabilities-URL, are readout from the 
						data base of map viewer. If in the GetCapabilities-URL specific data as e.g. to the organisation or address are lacking, some fields can not be filled.</p>

                    <p><b>Partner</b></p>
                    <p>Under Partner you will find the map services relevant for soil and soil related information belonging to different 
					data provider out of the GS Soil network and which are sorted by countries. </p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="305" height="157"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image204.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p> 
					<p>The meaning of the individual symbols are described under the <i>Topics</i> menu item (see above).</p>
						
                    <p><b>Metadatasearch</b></p>
                    <p>In the metadatasearch you can search for map services belonging to Partner, which are integrated in the GS Soil 
					map viewer. For this, enter a search term and click on <i>Ok</i>. </p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="308" height="148"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image205.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p> 					
					
					<p>In the search result list the following symbols are used:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="20" height="18"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image112.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add WMS to the active services:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding 
						service is added to the active services. If the service contains fewer than 11 layers, all layers are directly activated 
						in the map as well. If, however, the service contains more than 10 layers, these are not autmatically activated so as to 
						keep the load time low.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="19" height="19"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image113.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add WMS to the active services and zoom in:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the 
						corresponding service is added to the active services and, in the map, the map section described by the service is 
						zoomed in. Here the following also applies: if the service contains less than 11 layers, all layers will be also 
						activated directly in the map. If the service contains more than 10 layers, the layers are not automatically activated 
						to keep the load time low.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="15" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image110.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add layer to the active services:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding 
						layer is added to the active services.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="22"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image111.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add layer to the active services and zoom in:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol, 
						the corresponding layer is added to the active services and the map section described by the service in the map is 
						zoomed in. </p>
						
					<p>With one click on the name of the service or layer further information is displayed about the service or layer.</p>
					
                 </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-9">
                <header>Type of restriction</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you have chosen a map section you can select in which form the area restriction is to be used for the 
					GS Soil search. Here the following options are possible:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>The spatial reference for the search results lies within the map section chosen.</li>
                        <li>The spatial reference for the search results intersects the map section chosen.</li>
                        <li>The spatial reference for the search results encloses the map section chosen.</li>
                    </ul>
					                    <p> <img border="0" width="455" height="252"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image208.jpg"
                        alt="*"/></p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="ext-search-spacial-10">
                <header>Toolbar</header>
                <content>
                    <p>Via the toolbar you can carry out different actions directly or by clicking in the map.</p>
                   <p> <img border="0" width="319" height="27"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image207.jpg"
                        alt="*"/></p>			
                    <p>
                        <b>Adding WMS </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image024.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> You can add any GetCapabilities-URL (external service) by using this button. With the 
						<i>Add WMS</i> button the service is added to the active services and shown in map viewer.</p>
					<p> In doing this you can select (check box) whether the layer of the service is directly activated and 
					whether the service's map section is to be directly zoomed in on.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Information query</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image026.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> The information query in the map is directly activated via this button. The Informations were requested via a
						OGC WMS getFeature-Request to the integrated WMS service. By clicking once in the map you receive information specific 
						to the location in the layer shown.</p>
                    <p> Which information is displayed depends on which layer under <i>Active Services</i> has the check box 
					(infoquery in map) activated (see above). At present not all services support this function.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Display coordinates</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image027.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> Point coordinates can be called up in the map by this button. The position of the mouse is 
						displayed in geographic coordinates underneath the map. The coordinates of the last click in the map 
						are also displayed. </p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Zoom in - Select detail</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image031.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> You can zoom into the map with one click on this button. You can bring up any map section 
						by drawing up a square whilst holding down the left mouse button. The map is centred on this section 
						and correspondingly enlarged.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Zoom out - Reducing</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image032.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> The map is reduced in size by half with one click on this button.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Move map</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image033.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With this button the map can be dragged. To drag: click with the left mouse button on a point 
						in the map, hold the button down and pull the mouse over the map. After the operation the point on the map 
						clicked on will then to be found at the position where you release the button.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Back</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image034.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking on this button the map section displayed before the last action will be restored.</p>
                    <p>The action can be performed several times one after the other.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Forward</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image035.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> If you have gone back to a map section via the <i>Back</i> button, which is one or several 
						actions back, you can &#8218;leaf forward&#8217; to the actions performed after that by means of the 
						<i>Forward</i> button</p>
                    <p>The action can be performed as many times as the <i>Back</i> action was executed previously. </p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Show whole map</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image037.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking on this button the zoom is restored to the start extend of the map.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Print</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image039.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By means of this button a PDF-document of the map is produced with or without a key. You can 
						select the orientation of the map and in addition insert a title and commentary. You can print or save the 
						document via the usual PDF functions.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search: Time</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-time-1">
            <header>Time</header>
            <content>
                <p>GS Soil Portal is able to search for the time references of the connected systems. For this, on the one hand, the 
				data are used that the semantic service has analysed from the web pages as time references. On the other hand, the time 
				references in the databases are accessed. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-time-2">
            <header>Temporal Search</header>
            <content>
                <p>As a time reference you can either give a time frame (From/To) or a point in time (On the). In both cases the format 
				for giving the date is DD.MM.YYYY, that is two figures for the <b>D</b>ay, two for the <b>M</b>onth and four for the 
				<b>Y</b>ear.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-time-3">
            <header>Extension of search intervall</header>
            <content>
                <p>Basically all pieces of information are always found if their time reference is within the search intervals you have 
				entered. By crossing boxes you can also find information to which the following apply: </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The time reference of the results intersects the search interval entered.</li>
                    <li>The time reference of the results encloses the search interval entered.</li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Advanced Search: Search-Area</header>
        <section help-key="ext-search-area-1">
            <header>Content</header>
            <content>
                <p>Here you can ascertain whether you want to search through all soil information or whether you would only like 
				to search in publications. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-area-2">
            <header>Data Sources</header>
            <content>
                <p>In addition to web servers, metadatasystems and specialist data systems are also connected to GS Soil Portal. 
				You can choose whether you want to search in all these systems (default), or whether you would like to restrict 
				your search in a targeted manner to one or several kinds of data sources.</p>
                <p>If you limit your search to metadata then you also have the possibility of selecting the classes of metadata 
				that you would like to search. The following classes are available to you:</p>
                <ul>
					<li> Organisational Unit / Task</li> 
					<li> Geoinformation / Map</li> 
					<li> Document / Report / Literature</li> 
					<li> Geo-Service</li>
					<li> Enterprise / Project / Program</li>
					<li> Data Pooling / Data Base</li>
					<li> Service / Application / Information System </li>   

                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="ext-search-area-3">
            <header>Country/Provider</header>
            <content>
				<p>The data provided in GS Soil Portal come from the data provider out of the GS Soil network. You can limit the 
				information provided for your search to selected countries. It is also possible to choose several items.</p>
                <p>The different data provider belonging to a country are displayed if you click on the plus sign 
				<img border="0" width="9" height="9"
                        src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image018.jpg"
                    alt="*"/>. It is also possible to choose several items.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Search History</header>
        <section help-key="search-history-1">
            <header>Search History</header>
            <content>
                <p>GS Soil Portal stores a history of your search queries. As well 
				as this history, which is automatically carried for one session, you can also as a logged in user (see <a
                        href="help.psml?hkey=myingrid-1">myGS Soil</a>) save search queries permanently.</p>
                <p>You can call up both forms of stored search queries again via the <i>History</i> function.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-history-2">
            <header>Your last search queries submitted</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area your last search queries submitted are listed. By clicking on a search query 
				this is then loaded in the search window and the search is carried out.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-history-3">
            <header>Your saved search queries</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area your permanently saved search queries will be listed. By clicking on a search query this is 
				then loaded into the search window and the search is carried out. Saved search queries can be removed by putting 
				a cross and then using the <i>delete</i> button.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Options</header>
        <section help-key="search-settings-1">
            <header>Options</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can control the display of search results under the <i>Options</i> heading.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-settings-2">
            <header>Search Results Sorting &amp; Grouping </header>
            <content>
                <p>You can have your search results displayed either according to ranking 
				(relevance of the page found to your search term) or according to newness (the newest pages will be at the top).</p>
                <p><i>Grouping</i> means that the search results are displayed compiled according to coubtries, data providers or domains.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-settings-3">
            <header>Include similar terms in search</header>
            <content>
                <p>GS Soil Portal not only carries out the usual indexing found in search engines but also has the page contents analysed 
				by the semantic service. As a result of this analysis specialist terms from the thesaurus are assigned to the web pages.</p>
                <p>If you chose to include the setting <i>Include similar terms in search</i> by putting a cross, the associated similar 
				terms will be taken into account. (Note: In most cases the number of hits will be increased by selecting this setting.)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Tips &amp; Tricks </header>
        <section help-key="search-tipps-1">
            <header>You would also like to include similar terms in the search?</header>
            <content>
                <p>You have three possibilities for including similar terms in the search:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Automatically: in the <a
                        href="help.psml?hkey=search-settings-1">settings for the search Options</a> form 
                        cross the option <i>Include similar terms in the search</i>. You can also use these setting on a lasting basis (see <a
                            href="help.psml?hkey=myingrid-1">myGS Soil</a>).</li>
                    <li>Before conducting a search expand your search term with similar terms by using the 
                            <a
                        href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-subject-2">Topic/Thesaurus</a>
                        functionality of the <a
                            href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-1">Advanced Search</a>.</li>
                    <li>After a search you will be offered <a
                            href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-subject-5">Similar Terms</a> next to the search results list, 
							by means of which you can expand your search term.</li>
                </ul>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-tipps-2">
            <header>You would like to limit your search to information about the place you live in?</header>
            <content>
                <p>For this use <a
                        href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-spacial-1">Search Area</a>. You can either call up a search rectangle over the search area desired (<a
                    href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-spacial-6">By Map</a>) or enter your town (<a
                        href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-spacial-2">By geograhic Name</a>).</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-tipps-3">
            <header>You are only interested in information about your country?</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can select your country via the <a
                    href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-area-1">Search Area</a> of the search.</p>
                <p>You can also have these settings on a lasting basis (see <a href="help.psml?hkey=myingrid-1">myGS Soil</a>).</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-tipps-4">
            <header>You have a particular search query that you can't formulate via the advanced search?</header>
            <content>
                <p>GS Soil Portal allows complex search queries to be carried out that go beyond the possibilities 
				of the advanced search (e.g. grouping via bracketing or similarity search etc.). For this read section <a
                    href="help.psml?hkey=search-expert-1">Expert search</a>
                    in GS Soil Portal help and put your search term into the search field.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Save Query</header>
        <section help-key="search-save-1">
            <header>Save Query</header>
            <content>
                <p>After carrying out a search query the users logged in have the possibility of saving the search term used on a long-term basis (see 
				<a href="help.psml?hkey=myingrid-1">myGS Soil</a>) This takes place via the <i>Save Query</i> function.</p>
                <p>Note: The search queries last used are also accessible without saving for the session in progress via <a
                    href="help.psml?hkey=search-history-1">Search History</a>.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Expert Entry</header>
        <section help-key="search-expert-1">
            <header>Expert Entry</header>
            <content>
                <p>All settings of the advanced search and some further additional special settings can also be entered directly into the 
				search via the search string. As the syntax is very extensive because of the great number of search methods, it is meant for 
				experts in particular.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-2">
            <header>Boolean operators</header>
            <content>
                <p>The individual search terms can be linked via Boolean operators. The following operators are available:</p>
                <p>
                    <b>AND</b>: All the words have to be in the document. It is the standard if no operator is given. 
					(Note: instead of AND the symbol &amp;&amp; verwendet werden)<br/>
					For example: &#8218;water fish&#8217; equates to &#8218;water AND fish&#8217; or &#8218;water &amp;&amp; fish&#8217;</p>
                <p>
                    <b>OR</b>: One of the words has to be in the document. (Note: instead of OR the symbol || can be used)<br/> 
					Example: &#8218;water OR fish&#8217; equates to &#8218;water || fish&#8217;</p>
                <p>
                    <b>NOT</b>: : The word after NOT must not be in the document. (Hint: instead of NOT the symbol ! or the symbol | - can be used)<br/> 
					Example: &#8218;soil NOT ground&#8217; (the search is for soil but not for ground)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-3">
            <header>Grouping (bracketing)</header>
            <content>
                <p>The individual search terms linked by Boolean operators can be optionally grouped by bracketing (round brackets).</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;fish NOT (trout OR perch)&#8217; (all documents are found that contain the term &#8218;fish&#8217; but not the terms 
				&#8218;trout&#8217; and &#8218;perch&#8217;)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-4">
            <header>Search for word groups</header>
            <content>
                <p>If a string is placed in quotation marks (?), then the occurrence of the whole string is sought and not 
				the occurrence of the individual terms.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;The fish swims in the water&#8217; (Only texts are found that contain exactly this string.)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-5">
            <header>Wild cards</header>
            <content>
                <p>Within a search term it is possible to enter wild cards for one (?) or more (*) optional signs. 
				All terms are then found that match the rest of the search term whereby one or more signs can appear for the wild card.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;te?t&#8217; (Not only documents with the term&#8218;text&#8217; but also documents with the term  &#8218;test&#8217; will be found)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-6">
            <header>Search for areas of symbols</header>
            <content>
                <p>It is possible to search for areas of symbols. The areas are collected in square [] or curved {} brackets 
				and the bottom and top pieces of information are linked with the operator TO. Square brackets [] signify that 
				the lower and upper value of the area are included in the search. Curved brackets {} signify that the lower 
				and the upper value of the area are not included in the search.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;[Aller TO Elbe]&#8217; (Documents are sought that contain words that begin with all in the alphabet 
				and end at Elbe. The words &#8218;Aller&#8217; &#8218;Elbe&#8217; are included in the search area by this.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;{Aller TO Elbe}&#8217; (Documents are sought that contain words starting alphabetically with Aller 
				and ending at Elbe. The words &#8218;Aller&#8217; &#8218;Elbe&#8217; are not contained in the search area in this.</p>
				<p>The search area can also be given inside a search word. </p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;te[i TO x]t&#8217; (documents are searched for that contain, for example, the words teilt, test or text).</p>
				<p>As an alternative to the operator TO a hyphen &#8218;-&#8217; can also be used.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;te[i - x]t&#8217; (documents are searched for that, for example, contain the words tent, test or text).</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-7">
            <header>Fuzzy search</header>
            <content>
                <p>Documents are also found via the fuzzy search in which terms with similar spelling are found. 
				The fuzzy search is instigated by attaching a tilde (~) to the search term.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;Corn~&#8217; (documents will be found containing the term &#8218;horn&#8217; for example)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-8">
            <header>Special character</header>
            <content>
                <p>The following characters have a special meaning  in the GS Soil search string (e.g. in the form of operators):</p>
                <p>+ - &amp;&amp; || ! ( ) { } [ ] ^ &quot; ~ * ? : \</p>
                <p>Should you however use them as simple symbols within a search term then they must be marked as such by 
				the symbol \ (back slash).</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;\(1\+1\)\:2&#8217; (The expression &#8218;(1+1):2&#8217; is sought)</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-9a">
            <header>Search for special document types</header>
            <content>
                <p>In GS Soil Portal different document types can be searched for. For this the syntax &#8218;fileformat:value&#8217; is used.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;fileformat:pdf&#8217; (only PDF documents are searched for.)</p>
                <p>The following values are available for the &#8218;fileformat&#8217; field in GS Soil Portal:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Value</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description</b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>pdf </td>  
					<td> Only PDF documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>rtf  </td>  
					<td> Only RTF documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>msword </td>  
					<td> Only MS Word documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>msexcel  </td>  
					<td> Only MS Excel documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>mspowerpoint </td>  
					<td> Only MS-PowerPoint documents are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                </table>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-9">
            <header>Search for special datatypes</header>
            <content>
                <p>The GS Soil Portal full text index is organized in different fields. 
				All fields used in GS Soil Portal can be searched individually in targeted fashion. For this the syntax &#8218;field name:value&#8217; is used.</p>
				<p>In searching for a data type the field name is &#8218;datatype&#8217;</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;datatype:metadata&#8217; (documents are searched for that are arranged under metadata)</p>
                <p>The following values are available for the &#8218;datatype&#8217; field in GS Soil Portal:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Value</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description</b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>www</td>  
					<td> Only searched for websites</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>service</td>  
					<td> Documents from the Publication area are searched for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>metadata</td>  
					<td> Only searched for metadata</td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-13">
            <header>Search for a particular metadata class (data)</header>
            <content>
				<p>In searching for a particular metadata class the syntax &#8218;topic:value&#8217; is searched for.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;datatype:metadata metaclass:map&#8217; (metadata of the Geo-Information / Map class are being searched for.)</p>
                <p>The following values are available for the &#8218;metaclass&#8217; field in GS Soil Portal:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Value</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description</b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>job </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class 'Organisational Unit / Task' are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>map  </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class 'Geo-Information / Map' are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>document </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class 'Document / Report / Literature' are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>geoservice </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class 'Geo-Service' are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>project </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class 'Enterprise / Project / Programme' are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>database  </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class 'Data Pooing / Data Base' are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
					<td>service  </td>  
					<td> Metadata of the class 'Service / Application / Information System' are being looked for</td>
					</tr>
                </table>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-14">
            <header>Stating the spatial reference</header>
            <content>
				<p> The search can be restricted to documents that are associated with a certain spatial reference. 
				The spatial reference can be stated via coordinates or via the area key of the administrative unit.</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;areaid:2800866&#8217; (The search will be restricted to Berlin as administrative unit.)</p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;x1:3.44 y1:50.27 x2:5.25 y2:51.42&#8217; (The search is restricted to a selected rectangle.)</p>
                <p>The following fields are available in GS Soil Portal for the restriction of the spatial reference:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Field</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description of the Value </b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>areaid </td>  
					<td> Key of the administrative unit</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>x1  </td>  
					<td> left</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>x2 </td>  
					<td> right</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>y1 </td>  
					<td> up</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>y2 </td>  
					<td> down</td>
					</tr>
               </table>
			   <p> The coordinates have to be entered as degrees (WGS 84). </p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-expert-15">
            <header>Stating the time reference</header>
            <content>
				<p> The search can be restricted to documents that are associated with a particular time reference. </p>
                <p>Example: &#8218;t1:2009-06-01 t2:2010-12-31&#8217; (The search is restricted to a selected time interval.)</p>
                <p>The following fields are available in GS Soil Portal for the restriction of the time reference:</p>
                <table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" style="border-collapse:collapse;border:none">
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <b>Field</b>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <b>Description of the Value </b>
                        </td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>t0 </td>  
					<td> The document was associated with the time point stated</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>t1  </td>  
					<td> The document was associated with a time span that begins with the value stated</td>
					</tr>
                    <tr>
					<td>t2 </td>  
					<td> The document was associated with a time span that ends with the value stated</td>
					</tr>
               </table>
			   <p> The times stated must always be entered in the form YYYY-MM-DD (Y=year, M=month, D=day).</p>
            </content>
        </section>

    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Search result list</header>
        <section help-key="search-results-1">
            <header>Search result list</header>
            <content>
                <p>After submitting a search query you will receive the result list. It is broken down into the main result list (left column) 
				and the list with results from broader data sources (right column). You will also be given the possibility of refining your 
				search query via the <a href="help.psml?hkey=search-1">Search form</a> and to do another search. For this you can also use 
				the similar terms offered to you.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-results-2">
            <header>Main result list</header>
            <content>
                <p>In the main result list you will be shown the results from the search in the web pages of the connected server as 
				well as in the metadata systems in a list weighted according to relevance.</p>
                <p>Instead of the simple weighted list you can also have the results displayed <a
                    href="help.psml?hkey=search-settings-2#search-settings-2">grouped</a>
                    according to different countries or according to data providers or 
					<a href="help.psml?hkey=search-settings-2#search-settings-2">sorted</a> according to their actuality.</p>
                <p>If the information you have found is a web page then, as well as a series of pieces of information 
				(e.g. title, description and provider), you will receive a link by means of which you will be led directly 
				to the original page.</p>
                <p>If the information you have found is a metadata information you will be led via the link to the detailed representation 
				of the specialist information. In the cases, where there is a direct link available to a web page in which the meta- or 
				specialist information is available, then you will be offered this and will be led by this to the original page. In the cases 
				in which there is a map beyond, you will get a <i>Show map</i> link offered by means of which you can open the map in 
				GS Soil Portal map viewer.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-results-3">
            <header>Further data sources</header>
            <content>
                <p>As well as the metadata systems incorporated in the main result list, further information systems are also 
				interrogated via GS Soil Portal. The interfaces of these systems do not allow any integration of the search results 
				into the weighted main results list. The search results are therefore shown in a separate list sorted according to 
				data sources. In doing so the data sources are listed in the order of successful responses logged.</p>
                <p>You will be guided further via the links provided either directly to the individual search results or to a search 
				result list in the source system according to the data source.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-results-4">
            <header>Similar terms</header>
            <content>
                <p>GS Soil Portal offers you the possibility of expanding your search query by similar terms. For this, the search 
				string entered by you will be analysed by a semantic service integrated in the GS Soil Portal.</p>
                <p>If you click on the plus <img border="0" width="9"
                        height="9"
                    src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image018.jpg"/>sign you will be offered the similar terms for 
					each search term entered. These can be displayed again with the <img border="0" width="9" height="9"
                    src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image018.jpg"/>sign. By putting a cross next to the individual terms and clicking on the <i>Add to search</i> button, 
					the similar terms will be added to the associated search term each time such that a document will be found if either 
					the search term or the similar term are contained (OR linking).</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
		<header>Thesaurus browser</header>

        <section help-key="search-catalog-2">
            <header>Thesaurus browser</header>
            <content>
                <p>The representation of the body of words in a thesaurus takes place in a tree structure, starting with the 
				top terms of <a href="#ext-search-subject-3">GEMET</a>. When a thesaurus term (descriptor) is selected by clicking on it. In the <i>result list</i> all metadata entries are listed which include the selected 
				thesaurus term as keyword or search term. The list of metadata sets is grouped according to the different metadata
				catalogues. The detailed representation of a metadata set takes place after a query, i.e. by clicking 
				on its title, just as in the list of the search results in the free search. Switching between <i>soil information</i> 
				and <i>addresses</i> takes place in the area of the result list. </p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Publication</header>
        <section help-key="search-service-1">
            <header>Publication</header>
            <content>
                <p>Under &#8218;Publications&#8217; 
                    all press realeases out of the GS Soil network are collected.</p>
                <p>From this menu item you reach the corresponding pages of the data providers.</p>
            </content>
		</section>
        <section help-key="search-service-3">
            <header>Country</header>
            <content>
                <p>In this area you can select from which country you will search for publications.</p>
                <p>You can carry out multiple selections by holding down the ctrl-key and then clicking on the countries desired.</p>
                <p>If <i>select all</i> is selected then the information of all data providers is displayed.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="search-service-4">
            <header>Grouping</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can get the results displayed either according to the selected countries or according to the individual data 
				providers. This means that all information of a country or of a data provider are collected into a group and displayed 
				together.</p>
                <p>If you do not wish such a grouping you can select the <i>No</i> setting.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>Maps</header>
        <section help-key="maps-1">
            <header>Maps</header>
            <content>
                <p>With the GS Soil map viewer you can view diffent maps with soil and soil related informations. Select a map service 
				from the heading <i>Topics</i> or the heading <i>Partner</i> or add an external service. If you have reached map viewer via a 
				search result (<i>Show map</i>), the corresponding map will be displayed to you immediately.
                   </p>
            </content>
        </section>
            <section help-key="maps-2">
				<header>Tabs</header>
                <content>
                    <p>In the GS Soil map viewer map services, legends, metadata search and download service are sorted in 
					different tabs, which are situated to the left of the map. By clicking on a tab the respective menu item will be opened.</p>
					<p><img border="0" width="191" height="145"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image201.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>
                    <p><b>Legend</b></p>
                    <p>In the menu item &#8218;Legend&#8217; all available legends of the map layers are depicted, which are activated under 
					&#8218;Active Services&#8217; and are depicted as maps in the viewer. The legend gives information about which symbols 
					and/or colours are used to display the different information in the map.</p>
                   <p><b>Active Services</b></p>
                    <p>All map services found under &#8218;Active Services&#8217; can be activated or de-activated by one click in map viewer. 
					The map services with their layers are depicted in a tree structure.</p>
					<p><img border="0" width="306" height="94"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image202.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>					   
					<p>The single symbols have the following meaning:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image101.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Moves the section up:</b> A highlighted service and/or a highlighted layer is pushed upwards by one level. 
						A service or layer can be highlighted by clicking with the left mouse button on the name. For depiction in the map the 
						following applies: layers, which are listed further down in the tree structure, overlie layers that are listed further 
						at the top.</p>								
                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image102.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Moves the section down:</b> A highlighted service and/or a highlighted layer is displaced downwards by one level. 
						A service or a layer can be highlighted by clicking with the left mouse button on the name. If one layer is overlaid 
						by another one then this can be rendered visible by displacing downwards. The layer, which is at the bottom end of the 
						list, is always depicted as the uppermost layer in the map.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image114.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Remove the selected WMS:</b> A highlighted service is deleted from the &#8218;Active Services&#8217; area. A service can 
						be highlighted by clicking with the left mouse button on the name. It is not possible to remove individual layers.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="20" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image106.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Active services:</b> The folder symbol is used to display the <b>map services</b>. The corresponding layers 
						of a service are to be found in the individual folders. You can drag, remove the service or alter its transparency 
						with one click (left mouse button) on the folder symbol.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="16" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image107.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> This symbol is used to display one <b>layer</b>. You can drag the service, zoom onto the layer of the 
						service or call up information with one click (left mouse key) on the symbol.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="17" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image108.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Toggles the visibility of the service:</b> If the check box for a service or a layer is ticked 
						then the service or layer in the map is activated and shown in the map if the corresponding degree of zoom 
						(pre-defined standard for the layer) is set. Furthermore corresponding layer information can be summoned up 
						in the map via the &#8218;Query&#8217; (toolbar) button If the map section represented is outside the zoom level of the 
						layer then the layer in the map is not displayed and the layer title is represented in grey. If a service is 
						ticked then all the layers of the service are activated. If the tick is removed from a service then all the 
						layers of the service are de-activated.</p>
          
					<p> <img border="0" width="18" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image104.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Show metadata:</b> Further information (metadata) is displayed about a service.</p>

					<p><b>Topics</b></p>
                    <p>Under topics you will find different map services from data provider sorted according to soil topics and which can be 
					loaded into the GS Soil map viewer.</p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="304" height="203"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image203.jpg"				   
					     alt="*"/> </p> 
					   
					<p>The single symbols have the following meaning:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="17" height="17"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image109.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> The folder symbol is used for displaying different soil topics. In the folder you find the corresponding map services.</p>
 
                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="22"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image111.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add WMS to the active services and zoom in:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the 
						corresponding service is added to the active services and, in the map, the map section described by the service is 
						zoomed in. Here the following also applies: if the service contains less than 11 layers, all layers will be also 
						activated directly in the map. If the service contains more than 10 layers, the layers are not automatically activated 
						to keep the load time low.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image104.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Show metadata:</b> Further information (metadata) is displayed about a service.</p>

                    <p><b>Partner</b></p>
                    <p>Under Partner you will find the map services relevant for soil and soil related information belonging to different 
					data provider out of the GS Soil network and which are sorted by countries </p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="305" height="157"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image204.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p> 
					<p>The meaning of the individual symbols are described under the <i>Topics</i> menu item (see above).</p>
						
                    <p><b>Metadatasearch</b></p>
                    <p>In the metadatasearch you can search for map services belonging to Partner, which are integrated in the GS Soil 
					map viewer. For this, enter a search term and click on <i>Ok</i>. </p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="308" height="148"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image205.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p> 					
					
					<p>In the search result list the following symbols are used:</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="20" height="18"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image112.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add WMS to the active services:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding 
						service is added to the active services. If the service contains fewer than 11 layers, all layers are directly activated 
						in the map as well. If, however, the service contains more than 10 layers, these are not autmatically activated so as to 
						keep the load time low.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="19" height="19"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image113.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add WMS to the active services and zoom in:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the 
						corresponding service is added to the active services and, in the map, the map section described by the service is 
						zoomed in. Here the following also applies: if the service contains less than 11 layers, all layers will be also 
						activated directly in the map. If the service contains more than 10 layers, the layers are not automatically activated 
						to keep the load time low.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="15" height="16"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image110.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add layer to the active services:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol the corresponding 
						layer is added to the active services.</p>

                    <p> <img border="0" width="18" height="22"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image111.jpg"
                        alt="*"/><b>Add layer to the active services and zoom in:</b> With one click (left mouse button) on this symbol, 
						the corresponding layer is added to the active services and the map section described by the service in the map is 
						zoomed in. </p>
						
					<p>With one click on the name of the service or layer further information is displayed about the service or layer.</p>

					<p><b>Add new WMS services</b></p>
					<p>With help of this tab, data providers out of the GS Soil Network can enter easily new map services via this graphical 
					user interface which will stored directly in the database. After approval by the administrator these services will be available in the map viewer.</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section help-key="maps-3">
				<header>Search WFS</header>
					<content>
                    <p>The Download Service permits the user to query and download soil datasets from the GS Soil Portal, map viewer component. 
					These datasets are made available by the GS Soil data provider's network that is connected to the portal.</p>
					<p><b>NOTE: In the current version, no Rights Management component exists; therefore only public soil data is available.</b></p>
					<p>The sections below aim to help the user to use correctly and efficiently the download service.</p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="305" height="123"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/Search_WFS.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p> 					
					<p><u>Step 1 : select the download service option from map viewer</u></p>
					<p> <img border="0" width="304" height="238"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/Search_WFS_box.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>
					<p>The user should select the &#8218;Search WFS&#8217; tab. A tree list shall be presented, categorised by country name. When pressing the 
					<img border="0" width="13" height="13" src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/WFS_node.jpg" alt="WFS node"/> icon in a 
					tree element, e.g.: near the country name, a list of WFS services (children) shall be displayed. When pressed in the WFS service 
					name, it shall display all available WFS layers (children) of that service.</p>
					<p> <img border="0" width="307" height="238"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/Search_WFS_box2.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>
					<p>In the other hand, when the user presses the  
					<img border="0" width="15" height="16" src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/WFS_node2.jpg" alt="WFS node"/> icon, 
					at any level, country or service, all the children will be made invisible (it will collapse the tree at the selected level, i.e. 
					it will hide the layers or the services).</p>
					<p><u>Step 2 : select the layers to download data from</u></p>
					<p>When the user is satisfied with the layer selection from the desired WFS services (e.g.: user may select more than one layer, 
					from the same service or different services of the same or different countries). </p>
					<p> <img border="0" width="380" height="216"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/WFS_layer_sel.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>
					<p><u>Step 3 : zooming in layers </u></p>
					<p>Optionally the user can zoom in to the layers map extended by pressing the 
					<img border="0" width="16" height="16" src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/Zoom_layer_i.jpg" alt="Zoom to layer"/> icon on 
					the left of the layer name. This will centre and display the layer in the map viewer.</p>
					<p> <img border="0" width="450" height="297"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/Zoom_layer.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>
					<p><u>Step 4 : Show metadata</u></p>
					<p><img border="0" width="16" height="15" src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/Meta_button_i.jpg" alt="Layer metadata"/> 
					Further information (metadata) about a service and/or a layer is displayed for Web Feature Services. The information, which originate 
					from the particular GetCapabilities-URL, are readout from the data base of the map viewer. If in the GetCapabilities-URL specific 
					data as e.g. to the organisation or address are lacking, some fields can not be filled.</p>
					<p> <img border="0" width="450" height="254"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/Meta_button.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>
					<p><u>Step 5 : selecting a spatial filter (bounding box rectangle)</u></p>
					<p>After the selection of the layers the user must now select a spatial filter that shall be applied to the layers. This will limit 
					the amount of soil data that will be retrieved by this operation.</p>
					<p>In order to achieve that objective, a button is available in the toolbar above the map, the last button on the right. The user must 
					click on it, to make the tool active and afterwards it should draw over the map a rectangle (called bounding box). Click first and hold 
					the left mouse button on the map (this will set the top left corner of the rectangle) and then drag the mouse to the final location and 
					release the left mouse button (this will set the lower right corner of the rectangle).</p>
					<p> <img border="0" width="550" height="318"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/Spatial_filter.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>
					<p>To be noted, on the lower part of the map, the coordinates of the select spatial filter bounding box rectangle. </p>
					<p><u>Step 6 : executing or cancelling the query</u></p>
					<p>After the spatial filter is set (over the map)  the user may select the &#8217;download&#8217; button or the &#8217;new&#8217; button, both present below the 
					tree list of the Search WFS download service tab.</p>
					<p>While the last button will cancel the spatial filter - meaning the user should redo the spatial rectangle over the map or eventually cancel 
					the procedure - the download button will instruct the portal to execute queries to the select services and layers in order to acquire the 
					correspondent soil data(sets), if data is available for the selected area (spatial filter).</p>
					<p><u>Step 7 : displaying and downloading  data(sets)</u></p>
					<p>The portal will popup the number of result windows according to the number of selected layers. In each window it will be displayed the output 
					of the query to the layer, which can be one of the following: 
					<ul>
						<p>1.	A message informing that no data as found.</p>
						<p>2.	A message informing that the data found is too big.</p>
						<p>3.	A download link to the data found.</p>
						<p>4.	A download link to the data found and a tabular display of that data (example below)</p>
					</ul>
					</p>
					<p> <img border="0" width="532" height="400"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/WFS_result.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> </p>
					<p>The reasoning of the previous types of responses is as follows:
					<ul>
						<p>1.	The select spatial filter didn't intersect any data on the selected layer(s), i.e. the spatial extend of the layer wasn't intersected 
						by the user spatial filter bounding box rectangle. Therefore no data can be returned.</p>
						<p>2.	There is a limit of 16MB for the amount of soil data returned for each layer. If this limit is crossed no data is returned and the user 
						should narrow the spatial filter.</p>
						<p>3.	Another limitation is applied to the size of the data returned and the possibility of being displayed in a tabular format. If the returned 
						data size is greater than 8MB, only a download link shall be displayed allowing, at least, the data to be downloaded by the user.</p>
						<p>4.	When the returned data size is less or equal to 8MB the portal can display it in a tabular format - all columns and rows of information - 
						along with the download link for the user to copy the data into his computer.</p>
					</ul>
					</p>
					<p><u>Step 8 : continue work with the portal</u></p>
					<p>After the last step above, the user may wish to execute other queries to the same or other layers or eventually use other functionalities of the GS Soil Portal.</p>
					<p>He should close the output popup windows (with the results) and proceed from step 1; or just redo the spatial index and then proceed from step 5; or select 
					other services and layers and then proceed from step 2 or finally select other functionality from the portal.</p>
					</content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="maps-3">
                <header>Save Map</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you have registered with your account under &#8218;MyGS Soil&#8217;, you can save your settings under 
					&#8218;Active Services&#8217;. Therefor klick on the Link &#8218;Save map&#8217; above the legend. Below the 
					map viewer appeares a dialogue field, which offers the possibility to save the construction under a user-definded 
					name. After saving a definite URL is assigned, which is continued to use.</p>
                    <p> <img border="0" width="317" height="130"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image206.jpg"
                        alt="*"/></p>					
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="maps-4">
                <header>Toolbar</header>
                <content>
                    <p>Via the toolbar you can carry out different actions directly or by clicking in the map.</p>
                   <p> <img border="0" width="319" height="27"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image207.jpg"
                        alt="*"/></p>			
                    <p>
                        <b>Adding WMS </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image024.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> You can add any GetCapabilities-URL (external service) by using this button. With the 
						&#8218;Add WMSs&#8217; button the service is added to the active services and shown in map viewer.</p>
					<p> In doing this you can select (check box) whether the layer of the service is directly activated and 
					whether the service's map section is to be directly zoomed in on.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Information query</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image026.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> The information query in the map is directly activated via this button. The Informations were requested via a
						OGC WMS getFeature-Request to the integrated WMS service. By clicking once in the map you receive information specific 
						to the location in the layer shown.</p>
                    <p> Which information is displayed depends on which layer under &#8218;Active Services&#8217; has the check box 
					(infoquery in map) activated (see above). At present not all services support this function.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Display coordinates</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image027.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> Point coordinates can be called up in the map by this button. The position of the mouse is 
						displayed in geographic coordinates underneath the map. The coordinates of the last click in the map 
						are also displayed. </p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Zoom in - Select detail</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image031.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> You can zoom into the map with one click on this button. You can bring up any map section 
						by drawing up a square whilst holding down the left mouse button. The map is centred on this section 
						and correspondingly enlarged.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Zoom out - Reducing</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image032.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> The map is reduced in size by half with one click on this button.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Move map</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image033.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With this button the map can be dragged. To drag: click with the left mouse button on a point 
						in the map, hold the button down and pull the mouse over the map. After the operation the point on the map 
						clicked on will then to be found at the position where you release the button.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Back</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image034.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking on this button the map section displayed before the last action will be restored.</p>
                    <p>The action can be performed several times one after the other.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Forward</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image035.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> If you have gone back to a map section via the &#8218;Back&#8217; button, which is one or several 
						actions back, you can &#8218;leaf forward&#8217; to the actions performed after that by means of the 
						&#8218;forward&#8217; button</p>
                    <p>The action can be performed as many times as the &#8218;Back&#8217; action was executed previously. </p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Show whole map</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image037.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By clicking on this button the zoom is restored to the start extend of the map.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Print</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/image039.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> By means of this button a PDF-document of the map is produced with or without a key. You can 
						select the orientation of the map and in addition insert a title and commentary. You can print or save the 
						document via the usual PDF functions.</p>
					<p>
                        <b>Select download data</b>
                    </p>
					<p>
                        <img border="0" width="24" height="23"
                            src="../decorations/layout/ingrid-help/images/Sel_data_button.jpg"
                        alt="*"/> With this button a map section (bounding box) can be selected. After activating the button you can 
						click on a point in the map and, by holding down left mouse button draw up a rectangle. After then letting go 
						of the button the coordinates of the bounding box are displayed underneath the map.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>News</header>
        <section help-key="rss-news-1">
            <header>News</header>
            <content>
                <p>Under <i>News</i> listed current releases on the subject of the &#8218;soil&#8217; 
				from the project. Here the latest report is always on top. Each time only the title and a short description of the report are 
				displayed. By clicking on the report you will be taken to the original report.</p>
                <p>Older reports, which are no longer displayed on the home page, are stored in the report archive. You can look at these 
				reports by clicking on the &#8218;Additional News &#8217; link.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <header>MyGS Soil</header>
        <section help-key="myingrid-1">
            <header>MyGS Soil</header>
            <content>
                <p>GS Soil Portal offers you the possibility of putting your own settings in place on lasting basis. Using these you can:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Adapt the home page to your requirements</li>
                    <li>Personalise the search</li>
                </ul>
                <p>To do this you must register and receive a user name and a password. Registration is free. Your details will not be 
				passed on and are only used in anonymised form for statistical purposes.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-2">
            <header>Login</header>
            <content>
                <p>If you already have a user name and a password you can enter them here and click on &#8218;Sign-on&#8217;.</p>
            </content>
            <section help-key="myingrid-3">
                <header>New User</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you do not yet have a user name and password then click on the &#8218;New User&#8217; link. 
					This will take you to the &#8218;Login&#8217; form.</p>
                    <p>Please fill out the form. The detail fields with a star * are mandatory and must be filled in. 
					All other details are voluntary.</p>
                    <p>All details are handled in strict confidence and are only used for anonymised statistical evaluation.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-4">
                <header>Forgotten password?</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you have forgotten your password, click on the &#8218;Password forgotten?&#8217; link. You will then be 
					taken to the corresponding form in which you can enter your e-mail address. After submitting you will be sent 
					your user name and password by return.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-5">
                <header>Automatic Login</header>
                <content>
                    <p>If you would always like to use your personl settings you can select the &#8218;automatic login&#8217; option. 
					Then you will not have to enter your username and password every time to access the site. 
					(Note: this operation functions only if you have given your internet browser permission to use cookies).</p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-6">
            <header>Your personal GS Soil Portal home page</header>
            <content>
                <p>This link leads you to your personal home page as set up by you in the personalisation function.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-7">
            <header>Edit User Profile</header>
            <content>
                <p>This link takes you to the form with your details thus far. 
				If your details have changed, this is where you can update with these changes.</p>
                <p>The data fields with a star * are mandatory and have to be filled in. All other details are voluntary.</p>
                <p>All details are handled in strict confidence and are only used for anonymised statistical evaluation.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-8">
            <header>Personalisation</header>
            <content>
                <p>You can set the following settings according to your wishes.</p>
            </content>
            <section help-key="myingrid-9">
                <header>Personalisation of the GS Soil Portal Main Page</header>
                <content>
                    <p>In this area you can set which contents are to be displayed in which order on your personal home page. 
					For this you set the contents of lines 1 to 3 in the main column (on the left) of the home page via the dropdown list. 
					If you do not set your contents at all (empty entry in the dropdown list) this is also not displayed.</p>
                    <p>You can follow the same procedure for the margin column (narrower margin on the right side) of the home page.</p>
						
 				 <p>The determinations are not saved permanently as presetting. After klick on LOGOUT you return to the home page of 
				 GS Soil Portal with its own presettings.</p>
						
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-10">
                <header>Filter by Countries or Data Providers</header>
                <content>
                    <p>In this area you can regulate whether the information displayed for you is to be restricted to only 
					a country (e.g. Portugal) and/or to individual data providers (e.g. Portugal and INRB).</p>
                    <p>The settings relate to the search as well as to the publication areas.</p>
                    <p>The settings are saved permanently as preset settings.  However, you can overwrite them again temporarily 
					via the settings possibilities in the abovementioned areas (thus, for example, for individual searches).</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-11">
                <header>Filter by Types and Data Sources</header>
                <content>
                    <p>As well as the usual web servers, metadata and specialist data systems are also connected to GS Soil Portal. 
					You can now select whether you want to search in all data sources (standard) or whether you would like to restrict 
					your search in a targeted manner to one or several types of data sources.</p>
                    <p>If you limit yourself to metadata then you will continue to have the possibility of selecting the classes of 
					metadata you would like to search. The following classes are available to you:</p>
                    <ul>

                        <li>Organisational Unit / Task</li>
						<li>Geoinformation / Map</li>
						<li>Document / Report / Literature</li>
						<li>Geoservice</li>
                        <li>Enterprise / Project / Program</li>
						<li>Data Pooling / Data Base</li>
						<li>Service / Application / Information System </li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>The settings made will be effective on a lasting basis as preset settings. You can however overwrite them via 
					temporary settings for individual searches.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
            <section help-key="myingrid-12">
                <header>Sorting and grouping of search results</header>
                <content>
                    <p>You can display your search results either according to ranking (relevance of the page found with regard 
					to your search term) or according to actuality (the latest pages are shown first).</p>
                    <p>Grouping means that all search results of a page are collected in groups. Depending on the setting, all the 
					search results for countries or provider are collected together or those of all providers or domains.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>Include similar terms in the search </b>
                    </p>
                    <p>GS Soil Portal not only performs the usual indexing of the pages found on search engines but gets the 
						page contents analysed by the semantic service. As a result of this analysis, appropriate technical terms from the <a
                        href="help.psml?hkey=ext-search-subject-4#ext-search-subject-4">Thesaurus</a> are assigned to the web pages.</p>
                    <p>If you select the setting 
                        <i>Include similar terms in search</i> then these keywords will be taken account of in the search. 
						(Note: one should assume that selecting this setting increases the number of hits.)</p>
                    <p>The settings will be effective on a lasting basis as preset settings for the display of the search result list, 
						but can be overwritten via Settings in Search for individual searches.</p>
                </content>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section help-key="myingrid-13">
            <header>Logout</header>
            <content>
                <p>You leave the personalised area via LOGOUT and return to the home page of GS Soil Portal 
				with its standard preset settings.</p>
            </content>
        </section>
    </chapter>
</help>
